百萬  美元  寶貝
加油
Do it!
你能打敗他！你能打敗他！
You got him! You got him!
我只遇見過一個我不想和他爭斗的人
I only ever met one man I wouldn't wanna fight.
我止不了血
I can't stop that.
滾開吧，你個沒有的東西
Get out of here, you useless tit.
我遇見他的時候 他已經是拳擊界最好的傷口護理師
When I met him, he was already the best cut man in the business.
你能止住嗎？
Can you stop it?
從60年代起就開始做訓練師和經理人 一直保持著高昂的熱情
Started training and managing in the '60s, but he never lost his gift.
不行
No.
我來看看他
Let me have a look at him.
他沒事，他沒事
He's fine. He's fine.
如果你止不了血的話就不是沒事
He ain't if you don't stop this bleeding.
我再給你一個回合
I'll give you one more round.
- 時間到了，來吧    - 我們怎么辦？告訴我怎么辦
- Seconds out. Let's go.    - What do we do? Tell me what to do.
你讓他打你
You let him hit you.
有時你就是無能為力
Sometimes there's just nothing you can do.
傷口太深, 離骨頭太近
Cut's too wide, too close to the bone.
也許是斷了一條血管...
Maybe you got a severed vein...
...或者你就是無法讓止血藥深入里面
...or you just can't get the coagulant deep enough.
- 加油！    - 分開，分開
- Come on!    - Break. Break.
在肌肉的不同層次
There are all kinds of combinations you come up against...
你會遇到各種不同的問題組合
...down in the different layers of meat...
而弗蘭基全都知道如何解決
...and Frankie knew how to work every one.
- 對！加油！    - 你在做什么？
- That's it! Come on!    - What are you doing?
打倒他，威利！
Knock him out, Willie!
人們熱愛暴力
People love violence.
他們會在車禍現場 減慢車速查看死尸
They'll slow down at a car wreck to check for bodies.
就是這些人宣稱他們熱愛拳擊
Same people claim to love boxing.
他們根本不了解拳擊是什么
They got no idea what it is.
拳擊是有關尊嚴
Boxing is about respect.
贏得你自己的...
Getting it for yourself...
...同時剝奪對手的
...and taking it away from the other guy.
我先去發動車
I'll warm up the car.
鄧先生？
Mr.Dunn?
我欠你錢？
I owe you money?
沒有，先生
No, sir.
我認識你媽媽？
I know your mama?
這個我確實不知道，先生
Don't rightly know, sir.
- 那你想干什么？    - 我參加了墊場賽
- Then what is it you want?    - I was on the undercard.
而且我也贏了 我是麥琪 菲斯杰拉德
I won my fight too. Maggie Fitzgerald.
那么，麥琪 菲斯杰拉德，有什么事嗎？
Well, Maggie Fitzgerald, what's up?
- 你有沒有正好看了我的比賽？    - 沒有
- Did you happen to see it?    - Nope.
我干的不錯
I did pretty good.
我想你也許有興趣訓練我
Thought you might be interested in training me.
我不訓練女孩子
I don't train girls.
也許你應該試試 看我打過的人都說我很兇狠
Maybe you should. People see me fight say I'm pretty tough.
小姐, 光是兇狠并不夠
Girlie, tough ain't enough.
這是個錯誤
It's a mistake.
車應該能向后退的，弗蘭基
Car should be able to back up, Frankie.
幫我推一下，行不？
Just push, will you?
- 霍根有什么事？    - 邀請我們參加頭銜戰
- What did Hogan want?    - Offered us a title shot.
是時候了
About time.
我直接把他拒絕了
I turned him down flat.
再多打兩三場比賽 你就準備充分了
Two or three more fights, you'll be ready.
好久以前就說是兩三場比賽了，弗蘭基
Been two or three more fights for a long time now, Frankie.
聽著，威利 你只有一次機會贏得冠軍
Look, Willie, you get one shot at the title.
輸掉的話 可能就再沒有機會了
You lose it, it may not come around again.
再多打兩三場比賽 我們就準備充分了
Now, two or three more fights and we'll be ready.
都聽你的，弗蘭基
Whatever you say, Frankie.
弗蘭基總喜歡說 拳擊是一種不自然的運動
Frankie liked to say that boxing is an unnatural act...
因為拳擊中的每樣東西都是逆向的
...that everything in boxing is backwards.
有時...
Sometimes...
...打出一記重拳 的最好方法是退后一步
...best way to deliver a punch is step back.
我的主啊，請盡力...
Well, do your best, Lord...
...保護凱蒂
...protect Katy.
還有安妮
Annie too.
至于其他的...
Other than that...
...你知道我想要什么 所以我再重復也沒有什么用
...you know what I want, there's no use me repeating myself.
但是退后太多 你就已經退出比賽了
But step back too far, you ain't fighting at all.
（圣馬可教堂）
- 再見    - 再見
- Bye.    - Bye.
神父，布道很精彩，讓我流淚
Father, that was a great sermon. Made me weep.
你這周又有什么疑惑？
What's confusing you this week?
噢，就是那個老掉牙的三位一體的問題
Oh, it's the same old one-God-three-God thing.
弗蘭基, 大多數人幼兒園的時候 就知道一切都是信心的問題
Frankie, most people figure out by kindergarten it's about faith.
是不是有點象三種不一樣的薩其馬 都裝在一個大盒子里？
Is it sort of like Snap, Crackle and Pop all rolled up in one big box?
你站在我的教堂外面 把上帝比做點心？
You're standing outside my church comparing God to Rice Krispies?
你來做彌撒的唯一原因 就是要騷擾我
The only reason you come to Mass is to wind me up.
- 不過今天不會了    - 我有點迷惑
- It won't happen this morning.    - I'm confused.
- 不，你沒有    - 不，我有
- No, you aren't.    - Yes, I am.
那好，我給你的答案是： 只有一位上帝
Then here's your answer: There's one God.
還有事嗎？我很忙
Anything else? Because I'm busy.
- 那么圣靈呢？    - 他是上帝的愛的一種表現形式
- What about the Holy Ghost?    - He's an expression of God's love.
- 耶穌呢？    - 上帝之子，別在這兒裝傻了
- And Jesus?    - Son of God. Don't play stupid.
那么他是什么呢？ 上帝的兒子意味著半神半人？
What is he then? Does that make him a demigod?
沒有半神半人 操他媽的異教徒！
There are no demigods, you fucking pagan!
- 給你女兒寫信了么？    - 當然
- Did you write your daughter?    - Absolutely.
你這是對一個神父撒謊
Now you're lying to a priest.
跟你說吧，休息一天 明天別來了
You know what? Take a day off, don't come to Mass tomorrow.
（斗場拳擊館）
有些人會說對于一個拳手來說 最重要的莫過于熱情
Some people would say the most important thing a fighter can have is heart.
弗蘭基則會說 “給我一個只有熱情的拳手...
Frankie would say, "Show me a fighter who's nothing but heart...
...我會告訴他什么叫鼻青臉腫”
...and I'll show you a man waiting for a beating."
我想我只見過一個全心投入的拳手
Think I only ever met one fighter who was all heart.
我的名號是“戰斗小子” 丹吉爾 迪拉德 巴奇...
My name's Dangerous Dillard Fighting Flippo Bam-Bam Barch...
...來自德克薩斯布勞德縣！
...out of Broward County, T exas!
丹吉爾是幾年前來的
Danger showed up a couple of years back.
他和他媽媽的新男友艾瑞威爾 一起到洛杉磯來
He'd come visiting L.A. With Ervel, his mama's new boyfriend.
似乎艾瑞威爾迷了路 自己回去了德克薩斯
Apparently Ervel got lost and ended up back in Texas.
在來這里以前 丹吉爾找了他大概一個星期
Danger looked for him for about a week before he introduced himself.
嘿，你知道么 我對黑鬼從來沒有任何偏見
Hey, you know, I gots nothing against niggers.
呃，真高興聽你這么說
Well, that's nice to hear.
嗯，我的家鄉很多人確實是那樣...
Yeah, lots of people where I comes from does...
...但是我媽媽告訴我 不要傷害任何人...
...but my mama taught me not to cause hurt to no man...
...不管是不是黑鬼
...niggers or not.
你媽媽還真是個好人 我可以幫你點什么嘛？
You got a nice mama. Anything else I can do for you?
你也許只是隨便問個問題  ...
Just one of those questions you ask...
...但是丹吉爾總想給你最好的答案
...but Danger wanted to give it his best answer.
我想成為次中量級世界冠軍
Well, sir, I'd likes to become the welterweight champion of the world.
我要挑戰“城市機動眼鏡蛇”...
And I challenge the Motor City Cobra...
...還有“刺客”湯馬斯 赫爾斯...
...Thomas "Hit Man" Hearns...
...爭奪次中量級世界冠軍！
...to fight me for the welterweight championship of the whole world!
冒失鬼，閉嘴 你連排名都沒有
Yo, Flip, shut up, man! You ain't even ranked.
你最少要打一場比賽才能有排名
You gotta have at least one fight to be ranked.
嘿，我可以和任何人打，隨時！
Hey, I'll fight any man, anytime!
嘿，你是個壞蛋，是嗎？
Hey, you a bad man, huh?
進繩圈里來，我陪你玩一回合
Get in the ring. Go a round with me.
- 謝瑞爾    - 沒問題
- Shawrelle.    - I will.
別理他
Leave him alone.
丹吉爾, 你繼續訓練
Danger, you go on back to training.
我會的，斯科雷普先生
Will do, Mr.Scrap.
你的緊身褲不錯
Them's some nice tights, Danger.
我以后再揍你的屁股 小妞
I'll give you that ass-whupping later, Olive Oyl.
你的褲子還真不賴，丹吉爾
Hey, bro, those pants look real pretty on you.
把他媽媽的緊身衣還給她吧
Give his mama back her tights.
謝瑞爾 貝里的左鉤拳 可以打飛一輛坦克 ...
Shawrelle Berry had a left hook that would move a tank...
...但是他的心胸卻象豆子一樣小
...but he had a heart the size of a split pea.
弗蘭基17年前從巴比 馬龍 手里買下了斗場拳擊館
Frankie bought the Hit Pit from Bobby Malone 17 years ago.
巴比想搬到佛羅里達去 而弗蘭基想要生活有點保障
Bobby wanted to move to Florida, and Frankie wanted some security.
巴比在他收拾行李的時候死掉了
Bobby died while he was packing.
弗蘭基那時候才發現 大多數拳擊館都虧錢
And Frankie found out most gyms lose money.
我想我已經告訴過你 別讓丹吉爾繼續訓練下去了
I thought I told you I didn't want Danger working out here anymore.
他又不會傷害到別人，弗蘭基
He ain't hurting nothing, Frankie.
他傷害到我了
Well, he's hurting me.
我看著心疼 看他朝著空氣揮拳，好象空氣會反擊一樣
Breaking my heart, watching him punch the air like he thinks it's gonna punch back.
還有我告訴你多少次了 漂白液就是漂白液
And how many times have I gotta tell you that bleach is bleach?
你就不能買便宜點的么？ 不用買貴的那種
Why can't you buy the cheap stuff? You don't have to buy the expensive stuff.
這種更好聞一些，弗蘭基
It smells better, Frankie.
漂白液聞起來還是漂白液
Bleach smells like bleach.
- 嘿，斯科雷普    - 嘿，威利先生
- Hey, Scrap.    - Hey, Mr.Willie.
嘿，昨晚打得不錯
Hey, nice fight last night.
打得不錯
Nice fight.
- 大個子威利    - 嘿，賽利
- Big Willie.    - Hey, Sally.
- 打得不錯    - 謝了，兄弟
- Nice fight.    - Thanks, man.
有人在談話
People are talking.
這他媽的是什么語言？
What the hell kind of language is that?
你想干嗎？
What do you want?
我想你可能想知道 你有一個拳手...
I thought you might like to know you got a fighter out there...
...不跟別的經理人說話
...not talking to another manager.
不跟別的經理人說話？
Not talking to another manager?
不是隨便什么經理人
And not just any manager.
米奇 麥克
Mickey Mack.
你進來就是為了跟我說大個子威利 不跟米奇 麥克說話
You came in here to tell me that Big Willie is not talking to Mickey Mack.
他們兩個人，一個字都沒說
Not a word. Neither one of them.
我正打算讀書
I'm trying to read here.
好吧，如果你覺得讀書更重要
Well, if you think that's more important.
新來的那個女孩是誰？
Who's your new girl?
什么？
What?
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
最好快點
Better hurry up.
她要繼續這么打沙袋 手腕遲早會斷
She keeps hitting it like that, she gonna break her wrists.
你在浪費時間 我告訴過你我不訓練女人
You're wasting your time. I told you I don't train girls.
我想你也許會改變主意
Thought you might change your mind.
外面有至少一打訓練師訓練女人 找到一個很容易
Dozens of trainers train girls. You won't have any trouble finding one.
我不需要一打，老板 您一個就會很好
Don't hardly need a dozen, boss. You'll do fine.
別叫我老板，我不是你老板 你別再這么叫了
Don't call me boss, now. I'm not your boss, and don't you be calling me that.
- 威利，你準備好了么？    - 隨時可以開始
- Willie, you ready to work?    - Anytime.
如果我不叫你老板 你會訓練我么？
If I stop calling you boss, will you train me?
不會
No.
那我還是繼續這樣叫您好了
Then I might as well keep calling you it.
她從密蘇里州西南部來...
She came from southwestern Missouri...
...歐扎克地區的小城鎮 西奧多西亞城外的山上...
...the hills outside the scratch-ass Ozark town of Theodosia...
...一個雪松和橡樹環繞 比偏僻更偏僻的地方
...set in the cedars and oak trees somewhere between nowhere and goodbye.
在成長的過程中她只知道一件事： 自己是個垃圾
She grew up knowing one thing: She was trash.
是給我的狗的
It's for my dog.
盡管她可以跋涉1800英里 西奧多西亞還是就在那山上
She'd come 1800 miles, but Theodosia was still just over the hill.
我在打沙袋，老板
Working the bag, boss.
我不是你的老板 還有，是沙袋在打你
I'm not your boss. And that bag's working you.
把錢退給她
Give her her money back.
你確定？
You sure?
- 她付了多少錢？    - 六個月的
- How much did she pay?    - Six months.
- 我的老天    - 我去還給她
- Jesus Christ.    - No, I'll give it back.
不，別裝聰明了，好嗎？
No, don't be a smartass now, will you?
這女人一定會覺得咱們為了趕她走...
Woman thinks I'll throw away six months' worth of dues...
...連六個月的費用都不要 她肯定會發瘋的
...just to get rid of her, she's out of her mind.
- 但是千萬別鼓勵她，明白了么？    - 好
- But just don't encourage her, understand?    - Okay.
丹吉爾在外面做什么？ 他在看什么？
And what's Danger doing out there? What's he looking at?
好象是一瓶水
Looks like a bottle of water.
他付費了么？
He paid his dues?
費用？ 他連褲子都買不起，你想讓他付訓練費？
Dues? Boy can't afford pants. Want him to pay dues?
出去吧
Get out of my office.
我操
Fuck me.
你不能把它當做沙袋
Can't think of it as a bag.
我雖然不是訓練師 但是如果你愿意的話我可以示范一下
I'm not a trainer, but I can show you this if you'd like.
任何幫助我都會感激您
Appreciate any help I can get.
你要做的是 你要把它看成是一個人，明白嗎？
What you wanna do is, you wanna think of it as a man, see?
他在不停地移動
And he's constantly moving.
沖著你，繞著你 遠離你，明白嗎？
He's moving towards you, around you, away from you. All right?
不要在他向你移動的時候擊打他 因為他會把你向后推...
Don't hit him when he's coming towards you because he's just gonna push you back...
...化解你的擊打 讓你失去平衡，對嗎？
...he's gonna smother your punches and take your balance, right?
所以你要小心的注視他
So you watch him real carefully.
不停轉動 這樣你的頭就一直在動
Keep rotating. That keeps your head moving.
一個肩膀放在后側 這樣你隨時可以打出一記重拳
And keep one shoulder back so you're always ready to fire a power shot.
對嗎？來，好，好 不停旋轉，不停移動，好
Right? Go ahead, now. Good, good. Keep rotating, keep moving. That's it.
好，下巴收住
Good, good. Keep that chin tucked in.
繼續 不停移動，不停移動
Come on around. Keep moving, keep moving.
- 好，好，好    - 象這樣？
- Good, good, good.    - Like that?
對，給它幾下
Yeah. Give it a few shots.
下巴收住 下巴收住
Tuck that chin in, now. Tuck that chin in.
非常好，很好
Yeah, that's good. That's good.
等練完這個 我們就安排你打梨球
Now, you get this down, we'll put you on the speed bag.
你有梨球吧
You do have a speed bag.
我有錢買自己的之前先借用一下
I'll just borrow it till I can buy my own.
好，那你回家吧
All right, you go on home now.
- 我和你一起出去？    - 不用，這里就是我家
- I'll walk out with you?    - No, I am home.
- 想看看嗎？    - 嗯
- Wanna see?    - Yeah.
挺好的
It's nice.
我再打一會兒會不會打擾您？
Would it bother you if I worked a little longer?
不會，走的時候把門關好就行了
No, just pull the door closed when you leave.
謝謝
Thank you.
如果拳擊運動中有訣竅的話...
If there's magic in boxing...
...那么這種訣竅就是不停戰斗 超越耐力的極限...
...it's the magic of fighting battles beyond endurance...
...超越折斷的肋骨 破裂的腎臟，和脫落的視網膜
...beyond cracked ribs, ruptured kidneys and detached retinas.
這種訣竅是 為了別人無法了解的夢想而賭上一切
It's the magic of risking everything for a dream that nobody sees but you.
好了，好了，伙計們 看好腳步
Okay, okay, fellas, watch the footwork.
嘿，對了，對了
Hey, that's it. That's it.
手舉起來
Hands up.
刺，刺，刺
Jab, jab, jab.
嘿，冒失鬼
Hey, Flip.
嘿，冒失鬼，過來
Hey, Flippy, come here, man.
我想我找到一個你能打敗的人
I think I found somebody you can beat.
我不和女人打
I don't fights women.
為什么不，兄弟？太合適你了 你知道為什么嗎？
Why not, bro? It's perfect, bro, because you know why?
因為她--就象你 你可以和他打...
Because she... Like, you, you could fight to him...
...然后可以親親他
...and then you could kiss to him.
然后你還可以再跟他打一次
Then you fight to him one more time.
聽起來真美啊，哥們兒 象一首詩
That's beautiful, man. That's like poetry.
- 象一首詩    - 你他媽墨水不少啊
- It's like poetry.    - You been reading and shit.
- 謝了兄弟    - 伙計，這是個女人？
- Thanks, bro.    - That's a girl, man?
冒失鬼，我想你是對的 看看她的小奶子，就象蚊子咬的包
Flip, I think you right. Look at her little bitty titties. They're like mosquito bites.
靠，一嘴都含不滿 讓我看看
Man, that's barely even a mouthful. Let me see.
我看了你上一場比賽，謝瑞爾
Saw your last fight, Shawrelle.
大多數時間臉都朝下 我還意味地板長了奶子呢
Spent so much time face down, I thought the canvas had titties.
地板長了奶子 嘿，看看我，我是謝瑞爾
Canvas has titties. Hey, look at me. I'm Shawrelle.
跟拳臺做啊 跟地板做啊
Just humping the canvas. Humping the floor.
靠，兄弟，地板長了奶子？ 挺搞笑的，兄弟
Come on, bro. The floor having titties? That's funny, bro.
閉嘴吧你 你們笑什么呢
Shut up, man. What you laughing at?
哥們兒，扶住沙袋，傻瓜
Man, hold the bag, stupid.
那邊有奶子啊，哥們兒
Some titties right there, man.
冒失鬼，他們什么時候 開始做男式緊身褲了？
Yo, when they start making those tights for men, Flippy?
廢物
Punk.
好了，足夠了 今天足夠了
All right, that's enough. That's enough for the day.
- 我給你按摩一下    - 噢，我沒時間，弗蘭基
- I'll give you a rubdown.    - Oh, I can't, Frankie.
孩子有鋼琴課 我跟格蕾斯說我去送她
Middle one's got a piano lesson. I told Grace I'd drive her.
- 格蕾斯的車壞了？    - 她討厭那輛車
- Something wrong with Gracie's car?    - She hates that car.
想把那輛舊車要回來 可是賣車的說他已經有買家了
Wants the old one back, but the dealer said he's already got a buyer.
我也許應該和賣車的談談
Maybe I should talk to the dealer.
那我真是感激不盡
I'd appreciate that.
好吧
Okay.
- 謝謝    - 回頭見
- Thanks.    - See you later.
那家伙按摩成癮 今天他不想按摩
The man's a rubdown whore. Today he doesn't want one.
你在這里到底干不干活？
You ever do any work around here?
如果我是你的話 就不會操心我是不是干活
Not my job I'd worry about, if I was you.
小姑娘看起來有進步啊
Little girl seems to be coming along.
是啊，看起來好象甚至有人在訓練她
Yeah. It's almost like someone's been helping her.
也許她就是天生的 看起來她還有兩把刷子
She might just be a natural. Looks like she's got something.
她還有我的梨球 她有的就這么多
She's got my speed bag, that's what she's got.
我想知道她是怎么弄到的
I wonder how the hell she got that.
我也想知道
I wonder.
我想要拿回我的梨球
I'm gonna need that speed bag back.
- 這個？    - 沒錯，它是我的
- This bag?    - Yes, that bag. That's my bag.
如果你在這里打它 別人會認為我在訓練你
And if you're hitting it, people will think I'm training you.
老板，這件事就這么糟糕么？
Is that such a bad thing, boss?
對，對，沒錯
Yes. Yes, it is.
你每碰一次這個球 我就損失一些生意
Every time you touch it, you're losing me business out here.
- 我得承認，我在這兒是丟人現眼    - 嗯
- I gotta agree, I am embarrassing myself.    - Yeah.
你知道，我不能把這個隨便借給別人
Well, I can't just lend it to anybody, you know.
我理解
I understand.
嗯
Yeah.
你看起來是個不錯的女孩
Look, you seem like a nice girl.
- 我可以給你些建議么？    - 感激不盡
- Can I give you some advice?    - I'd appreciate that.
你可以在這里或者其他地方...
You'll find a trainer in this gym or somewhere else...
...找到愿意訓練女孩的訓練師
...that's gonna wanna train a girl.
簡直就象是馬戲表演
It's the latest freak show out there.
問題是，他們只會浪費你的時間...
The trouble is, they're gonna be wasting your time...
...因為你已經太老了
...because you're too old.
我不覺得我那么老了
I don't feel that old.
這個嘛，我也不覺得我老 但是你看我還會和21歲的人打拳么？
Well, neither do I, but you don't see me fighting 21-year-olds, do you?
訓練一個拳擊手要四年
Takes about four years to train a fighter.
你多大了？
How old are you?
- 在下個生日之前31歲    - 噢，對呀，你看看
- Thirty-one until my next birthday.    - Oh, well, there you go.
31歲了
Thirty-one.
你不會從31歲才開始練芭蕾舞，不是么？
You wouldn't start training to be a ballerina at 31, would you?
我已經練了大概三年了
Already been working it for three years.
那你連梨球都打不到？ 你到底怎么訓練的？
And you can't hit a speed bag? What kind of training is that?
從來沒有人指導，老板
Never had any, boss.
我不想說，可是能看出來
Well, I hate to say it, but it shows.
但是必須有人跟你說實話
Somebody's gotta be honest with you.
我討厭自己是那個說實話的人
I hate to be the one to tell you the truth.
嗯
Yeah.
呃，對不起用了您的球，鄧先生
Well, sorry for using your bag, Mr.Dunn.
- 你現在不會哭吧？    - 不會，先生
- You're not gonna cry now, are you?    - No, sir.
好吧
Yeah.
給
Here.
- 這個該死的東西你留著吧    - 不，你需要它
- Keep the goddamn thing.    - No, you need it.
不，拿著吧
No, take the bag.
反正我都二十年沒見過它了
I haven't seen it in 20 years anyway.
我還有三個 好好享受它，好嗎？
I've had three since then. Just enjoy it, will you?
- 我只是在自己買之前暫時借用一下    - 嗯
- I'll just borrow it till I buy my own.    - Yeah.
別丟了就行
Just don't lose it.
對，我知道，霍根...
Yeah, I know, Hogan...
...你的拳手是冠軍 所以我們不能對半分...
...your guy's the champ, so we don't split 50s...
...但是如果我連四成--
...but if I don't see 40 percent...
聽著，你同意六四開的時候再給我電話 要不然就別打來了
Look, you call me back when it's 60-40 or don't call me back at all.
- 嘿，威利    - 嘿，弗蘭基
- Hey, Willie.    - Hey, Frankie.
出什么事情了么？
Something wrong?
對不起我就這么來找您 我知道你不喜歡別人來串門
I'm sorry to come by your house like this. I know you don't like people dropping in.
噢，你可不是外人，威利 什么時候來我都歡迎，進來吧
Oh, you're not people, Willie. You're welcome anytime. Come on in.
我是來謝謝您幫格蕾斯把車拿回來
I wanted to thank you for getting Gracie's car back.
哦，你不用謝我
Oh, well, you don't have to thank me.
為自己的車多花1000美元 也不算幫什么忙
Paying an extra thousand dollars for your own car ain't exactly a favor.
格蕾斯看見那輛車的時候都哭了
Gracie cried when she saw it.
真的？
Really?
我還想跟您談談業務上的事情
I also needed to talk with you about business.
噢，對了，我剛和霍根通了電話 九月份的冠軍賽都談好了
Oh, yeah, well, I just got off the phone with Hogan. We're all set for September.
除了分成的問題
Everything but the split.
我得離開你了，弗蘭基
I gotta leave you, Frankie.
什么？
What?
威利，再打兩場就到冠軍賽了
Willie, the title's just two fights away.
不是這個問題，是-- 就好象你說的, 我只有一次機會
It ain't that, it's... It's like you said, I got one shot.
如果我贏了，我就可以在我還能掙 的時候掙盡可能多的錢
If I win, I gotta make as much as I can while I can.
我需要有人能幫我實現
I need somebody in the action who can make things happen.
而且我得在比賽前換經理人
And I gotta make the change before the fight.
他說必須讓他帶我去打冠軍賽 他才會簽下我
Only way this guy say he'd take me is if he took me to the title.
所以我給你安排冠軍賽 然后他帶你去參加
So I get you the title fight, and this guy takes you there?
他說必須這樣
Only way he'd do it.
很抱歉，弗蘭基 我知道你等冠軍很久了
I'm sorry, Frankie. I know how long you waiting on a title.
我也希望能和你一起
I wish it could've been with me.
米奇 麥克是個生意人 他什么也教不了你
Mickey Mack's a businessman. He can't teach you nothing.
你已經教會了一切我需要知道的
You already taught me everything I need to know.
有些話人們永遠都不愿意聽
There's some things people just don 't want to hear.
我要挑戰“城市機動眼鏡蛇” 還有“刺客”湯馬斯 赫爾斯...
And I challenge the Motor City Cobra, Thomas "Hit Man" Hearns...
......爭奪次中量級世界冠軍！
...to fight me for the welterweight championship of the whole world.
丹吉爾，我這個拳套不是白戴的
Danger, I'm wearing these mitts for a reason.
只是練習一下我的步伐 斯科雷普先生
Just working on my footwork, Mr.Scrap.
丹吉爾，你打一拳 要不然就滾出去
Danger, you throw a punch or get the hell out of this gym.
丹吉爾，好好想想那一拳 我馬上就回來
Danger, while you thinking about that punch, I'll be right back.
我想我會狠狠打那一拳，斯科雷普先生
I'm thinking how I'm gonna hit it hard for you, Mr.Scrap.
沒人忍心告訴丹吉爾 赫爾斯好多年前就已經退休了
No one had the heart to tell Danger that Hearns retired years ago.
威利的事情我聽說了
I heard about Willie.
非常無情，太無情了
That's cold. That's dead cold.
當然，要不是你年紀都這么大了 還不算太殘酷
Of course, it wouldn't be so bad if you weren't so damn old.
嗯，至少我還能用兩只眼睛看
Yeah, well, at least I can see through both eyes.
不過也沒給你帶來多少好處，不是嗎？
Didn't do you a lot of good though, did it?
我還有這個訓練館
Well, I've got the gym.
我這個年紀也不用再訓練拳手了
Don't need to be training fighters at my age.
威利告訴你原因了？
Willie tell you why?
是米奇 米奇有他的關系
It was Mickey. Mickey's got the connections.
這不是因為關系 這是因為你對他沒有信心
Oh, it ain't about connections. It's about you not believing in him.
我發掘了他 在他身上花了八年的心血
Well, I found him, I stuck with him for eight years.
這叫我對他沒信心？
How's that for not believing in him?
兩年前你就可以讓他去打冠軍賽了 他是知道的
You could've got him a title fight two years ago. Hell, he knew that.
他能在你身邊呆這么久 我都感到吃驚
I'm amazed he stayed around this long.
這個嘛，去參加比賽 和把腰帶贏回家完全是兩回事
Well, getting there and taking home the belt are two different things.
我應該怎么辦 讓他去參加贏不了的比賽？
What was I supposed to do, just put him in over his head?
不保護他？
Not protect him?
哦，你是在保護他不讓他拿冠軍？
Oh, you were protecting him from the championship.
- 對    - 唔，現在聽起來合情合理了
- Yeah.    - Well, now it makes sense.
那你又怎么樣呢，斯科雷普？ 你的經理當時做了什么？
Well, what about you, Scrap? What did your manager do?
你曾經是多么優秀的拳手 比威利要棒
You were a hell of a fighter, better than Willie.
他給了你一場冠軍賽 還是把你扔在那里...
He get you a title fight, or did he just bust you out...
...讓對手用拳頭不停打你的頭 直到把眼睛打沒了？
...banging your head against other people's fists until you lost your eye?
至少我有個機會
I had my shot.
我去揮舞過我的拳頭 沒有人能說我沒努力過
I went out swinging, and no man can say I didn't.
是啊，我記得
Yeah, well, I remember.
但是請不要因為 我不想讓我的拳手下半輩子...
And excuse me if I didn't want my fighter spending the second half of his life...
- ...都在清掃別人吐在地上的口水而介意    - 嗯，是啊
...cleaning up other people's spit.    - Yeah, right.
對，你是聰明人 你還學希臘語呢
Right, you're the smart one. You're the one learning Greek.
是高盧語
It's Gaelic.
你剛剛把自己參加 冠軍爭霸戰的機會保護沒了
Well, you just protected yourself out of a championship fight.
這句話用高盧語怎么說？
How do you say that in Gaelic?
抱歉
Sorry.
謝謝
Thanks.
冠軍和大個子威利 瓊斯 之間的較量繼續進行...
The action continues as the champ is battling Big Willie Jones...
...他被冠軍用 連續的左右拳控制住了
...and commanding him with rights and lefts.
逼到了繩圈的邊上 他在用左拳攻擊....
Up against the ropes, he's hitting him with the left...
拳擊是一種不自然的運動
Boxing is an unnatural act.
因為拳擊中的每樣東西都是逆向的
Because everything in it is backwards.
你想向左移動...
You wanna move to the left...
... 不是向左邁步 而是右腳趾用力
...you don't step left, you push on the right toe.
向右移動的時候左腳趾用力
To move right, you use your left toe.
你要迎著痛苦而上 而不是...
Instead of running from the pain, like a sane person would do...
...象有理智的人那樣躲避
...you step into it.
大個子威利反擊了，噢，天哪 他一記右手拳擊中了衛冕拳王
But Big Willie comes back. Oh, my God, he hits the champ with a right hand.
衛冕拳王倒下了
And the champ is down.
女士們先生們 裁判正在數點
Ladies and gentleman, the ref is in for the count.
大個子威利 瓊斯 成為了新的世界冠軍
And Big Willie Jones is the new champion of the world.
今晚發生的一切令人難以置信...
It's unbelievable how this has taken place tonight...
...不過朋友們，新的冠軍產生了
...but there you have it, folks, a new champion.
拳擊中的每樣東西都是逆向的
Everything in boxing is backwards.
要芝士漢堡嗎？
Want a cheeseburger?
- 你給我買了個芝士漢堡？    - 嗯
- You bought me a cheeseburger?    - Yeah.
我從沒見你給別人買過芝士漢堡
I never see you buy anybody a cheeseburger.
我點了，可我吃不了，你愿意吃么？
Well, I couldn't eat it, and I ordered it. You want it?
噢，我猜地球又開始轉了
Well, I guess the planet can go back to spinning.
- 你看比賽了么？    - 嗯，看了
- You watch the fight?    - Yeah, I watched it.
威利打的不錯
Willie did good.
這就是你要說的？
That's what you've got to say?
威利贏了，不是嗎？ 他打的不錯
Well, he won, didn't he? He did good.
我看出你正在改變自己 學著敞開心扉，很不錯
I see you been working on yourself, learning to open up. That's good work.
你看了？
You watch it?
是啊，我有HBO臺
Yeah, I got HBO.
你怎么可能看得起HBO？
Now, how can you afford HBO?
我從什么時候起就叫你省錢了？
How long have I been telling you to save your money?
從我和“臺風”路易斯 強森...
Ever since I fought Louis "Typhoon" Johnson...
...在密西西比州圖皮洛市的 俱樂部體育館比賽以后
...at the Stadium Club in Tupelo, Mississippi.
- 真的？    - 是的
- That true?    - Yeah.
經理人跑路了 讓我們自己搭車回家
Manager ran off and left you and me to hitch home.
你難道什么都不記得了么？
Don't you remember nothing?
我記得走到一半的時候 覺得自己要被私刑處死了
Well, I remember walking halfway and thinking I was gonna be lynched.
我記得你把口袋空空的我 扔在那個加油站
I remember you leaving me with my dick in my hand behind that gas station.
是啊，我當時搭到一個便車 我一關上門那家伙就開走了
Yeah, well, I got a ride. The guy took off before I hardly closed the door.
后來我不得不又往回走了兩英里
I had to walk back two miles.
你的良心占了上風 這就是原因
Your conscience got the better of you, that's what.
那他媽是什么聲音？
What the hell's that?
今天是她的生日
It's her birthday.
你的呼吸方法不對 這就是為什么你大口喘氣
You're not breathing right. That's why you're panting.
今天是你生日，是嗎？
So it's your birthday, huh?
那你多大了？
How old does that make you?
我32了，鄧先生
I'm 32, Mr.Dunn.
我在這里慶祝 我又花了一年的時間洗盤子和當女招待
I'm celebrating that I spent another year scraping dishes and waitressing...
我從13歲就開始干這些了
...which is what I been doing since 13.
根據您的理論 我37歲之前打不出一記象樣的拳...
And according to you, I'll be 37 before I can even throw a decent punch...
...打了這個梨球一個月 一點進展也沒有...
...which after working this speed bag for a month and getting nowhere...
...我現在認識到 上帝的現實也許就是這樣
...I now realize may be God's simple truth.
另外的現實是，我的哥哥在監獄里
Other truth is, my brother's in prison...
我的妹妹假裝 自己的一個孩子還活著，詐騙福利金
...my sister cheats on welfare by pretending one of her kids is still alive...
我爸爸死了 我媽有312磅重
...my daddy's dead, and my mama weighs 312 pounds.
如果我還有理智的話 我應該回家去
If I was thinking straight, I'd go back home...
找個二手的活動房屋 買個炸鍋，再來點夾心餅干
...find a used trailer, buy a deep fryer and some Oreos.
問題是，這是唯一我喜歡做的事情
The problem is, this is the only thing I ever felt good doing.
如果對于拳擊來說我太老了 那我就一無所有
If I'm too old for this, then I got nothing.
這下你滿意了吧？
That enough truth to suit you?
這是你的梨球？
This your speed bag?
把你的放在臺子后面了 真希望能說那是我用壞的
Put yours behind the counter. Wish I could say I wore it out.
好了，停一下，停一下
Okay, just hold it. Hold it.
我要教你幾件事情 然后給你找個訓練師
I'll show you a few things, and then we'll get you a trainer.
不用了，抱歉
No, sorry.
- 你還打算討價還價？    - 是的，先生
- You're in a position to negotiate?    - Yes, sir.
是的，因為我知道如果你正確的訓練我 我會成為冠軍
Because I know if you train me right, I'm gonna be a champ.
我見過你看著我的樣子
I seen you looking at me.
- 是的，用憐憫的眼神    - 你不要這么說
- Yeah, out of pity.    - Don't you say that.
你不要這么說，如果不是事實的話
Don't you say that if it ain't true.
我要的是訓練師
I want a trainer.
我不要施舍 我也不要幫忙
I don't want charity, and I don't want favors.
如果你不感興趣，那我還要繼續慶祝
If you're not interested, then I got more celebrating to do.
停，停，停
Stop, stop, stop.
該死，停下來 你到底在做什么？
Goddamn it, stop. What the hell are you doing?
好吧
Okay.
如果我來教你--
If I'm gonna take you on...
- 你一定不會后悔的    - 聽我說就行了
- You won't never regret it.    - Look, just listen to me.
- 如果我來教你--    - 我保證我會非常努力
- If I take you on...    - I promise I'll work so hard.
天，這已經是個錯誤了
God, this is a mistake already.
我聽著呢，老板
I'm listening, boss.
如果我來教你，你一句話也不要說 你不能對我有疑問
If I take you on, you don't say anything, you don't question me.
不要問我問題 除了“是，弗蘭基”以外什么也不要說
You don't ask why, you don't say anything except maybe, "Yes, Frankie."
還有我會試著忘記 你是個女孩這個事實
And I'm gonna try to forget the fact that you're a girl.
我就要求這么多
That's all I ask.
另外如果你受傷了別對我哭
And don't come crying to me if you get hurt.
- 好的    - 我們一言為定
- Alrighty.    - We got a deal.
沒，還沒有
No, not quite.
我教你怎么打拳
I'm gonna teach you how to fight...
然后給你找個經理人 我就放手不管了
...then we'll get you a manager, and I'm off down the road.
- 我不想和你爭，不過--    - 別跟我爭，我們就這么辦
- I hate to argue with you, but...    - Don't argue, that's the way we're doing it.
我會教你一切你需要知道的 然后你自己去掙個一百萬美元
I teach you all you need to know, and you go off and make a million dollars.
我不管 被人打掉牙齒，我也不管
I don't care. You get your teeth knocked out, I don't care.
我不想聽 這個東西就是這樣
I don't wanna hear about it. That's just the way it's gonna be.
只有這樣我才同意教你
It's the only way I'll do it.
好的
All right.
在訓練場里我注意到一件事 你從來不移動你的腳
Now, one of the things I've noticed around the gym is you never move your feet.
你總是呆呆的站在那里 你必須要移動你的腳
You stand there just flat-footed. You've gotta move your feet.
這是我將教會你最有用的東西之一
That's one of the best things I can teach you.
那么，你應該這么做
So here's what you do.
把自己-- 膝蓋彎曲一點
You get yourself... Bend your knees a little bit.
擺好運動姿態 就好像你打算要打什么一樣
Get in an athletic position. Look like you're gonna hit something.
- 怎么做，老板？    - 就--打--梨球就行了
- Move them how, boss?    - Just... Go... Hit the bag.
- 停    - 我做錯什么了？
- Stop.    - What'd I do wrong?
好，你做錯了兩件事情
Okay, you did two things wrong.
第一，你問了我一個問題 第二，你又問了一個問題
One is you asked a question, and two is you asked another question.
現在我要你做的 不是要打得多么狠
Now, what I want you to do, it's not about hitting it hard...
而是打得多么好 所以看著我
...it's how good you hit it. So watch me.
如果你愿意的話可以和我一起數
You can count with me if you want.
就是數數 數一的時候，我打一下球
It's just count. On a one-count, I hit right through the bag.
- 你能再示范一次么？    - 數--
- Can you show me that again?    - I just...
數一就行了，拜托
Just say "one," please.
- 一    - 好
- One.    - Okay.
- 一，好    - 一
- One. Okay.    - One.
對，就說一 很好，很好
Yeah, just say "one." That's good. That's good.
然后我移動到我的右腳 你可以看到我的重心都轉移到右腳
Then I move over to my right foot. You'll see my weight is shifting to my right foot.
然后我用我的手背攻擊 就象用冰錐碎冰
Then I hit it with my back of my hand, sort of like I'm chipping ice with an ice pick.
然后我轉過來，轉移到我的左腳 然后用右手攻擊
Then I come over, and I shift to my left foot, and I hit it with my right hand.
還是冰錐的動作
And ice pick maneuver again.
再轉到右腳上 再攻擊右側
And I come over on my right foot and hit it right.
就看著我的腳步
Don't watch anything but my feet.
就這么做 不停練習
Just do it like that. Just keep practicing.
你示范他們怎么站立 雙腳和肩膀平行
You show them how to stand, keep their legs under their shoulders.
訓練一名拳手 你必須在精神上把他們剝光
To make a fighter, you gotta strip them down to bare wood.
死了再休息
Rest when you're dead.
過來
Come here.
你不能只是 叫他們忘記以前知道的事情...
You can't just tell them to forget everything you know...
... 你要叫他們從骨子里忘記
...you gotta make them forget it in their bones.
讓他們疲憊到只聽你的話
Make them so tired they only listen to you.
只能聽見你的聲音 只做你叫他們做的事情，不做其他事
Only hear your voice, only do what you say, and nothing else.
腳步移動
Move your feet.
腳步移動起來 移動起來讓我看
Move your feet around. Let's see you go.
教他們怎么保持平衡 怎么讓對手失去平衡
Show them how to keep their balance and take it away from the other guy.
別這么低，看著我 右勾拳，然后向右
Not so low. Look at me. Right hook and just turn right.
如何用右腳趾產生動力
How to generate momentum off your right toe.
出刺拳時如何彎曲膝蓋
And how to flex your knees when you fire a jab.
如何在后退中攻擊 好讓對手在追擊你時有所顧忌
How to fight backing up, so that the other guy doesn't wanna come after you.
然后你要再全部教他們一遍
Then you gotta show them all over again.
一遍又一遍...
Over and over and over...
...直到他們感覺一切與生俱來
...till they think they were born that way.
轉移
Shift.
轉移位置
Shift away.
好了，今天就到這里
Okay. That's enough for today.
不錯，好姑娘
Good work. Good girl.
老板，你覺得我可以打比賽了么？
You think I ready for a fight, boss?
嘿，你過來
Hey. Hey, come here.
你都喘不過氣了
You're not breathing.
不想和你爭論
Hate to disagree with you.
你一有壓力就喜歡屏住呼吸
Every time you get under pressure, you're holding your breath.
- 從現在開始別這么做    - 好的
- Now, stop doing that.    - Okay.
除了這一點，我做得很好，是吧？
But other than that, I'm doing pretty good, right?
- 我是說，對于女孩來講    - 我不訓練女孩
- I mean, for a girl.    - I don't train girls.
老板，你覺得我可以參加比賽了么
Think I might be ready for a fight, boss?
嗯，我們先找個經理人 然后我們再看看，好嗎？
Well, we'll get a manager, and we'll find out, won't we?
我是想找一個 可是你一直讓我抽不出時間來
I'd like to, but you been keeping me too busy.
- 有家人嗎，老板？    - 什么？
- Got any family, boss?    - What?
我看你把所有的時間都花在我的身上了 我不知道你有沒有家人
You been spending all this time with me, I didn't know if you had any.
沒有
No.
呃，我是有個女兒，叫凱蒂
Well, I've got a daughter, Katy.
她就是家人啊
That's family.
但是我們并不那么親近
We're not exactly close.
她多重？
How much she weigh?
什么？
What?
我的家庭問題和體重成正比
Trouble in my family comes by the pound.
是嗎
Yeah.
不是很重
Not very big.
曾經很愛運動 不知道現在還有沒有堅持
Used to be real athletic. Don't know if she kept it up.
那么，你怎么想？
So, what do you think?
我可以參加比賽了么？
I ready for a fight?
嘿，賽利
Hey, Sally.
過來一下，好嗎？
Come here for a minute, will you?
弗蘭基，能不能到后面來跟我談談？
Frankie, I need to see you in the back for a minute, okay?
- 我能和你說句話么？    - 賽利是個很優秀的經理人
- Can I see you a minute?    - Sally here's a real good manager.
他手下還有幾個拿過金手套的選手 想要女孩嗎，賽利？
Has a couple of Golden Glove boys. Looking for a girl, Sally?
如果有優秀人選的話
I'm looking for a good one.
看，這不就有了
Well, see, there you go.
很高興和你合作，小姐
Nice working with you, girlie.
- 你有什么事？    - 沒什么，沒什么
- What'd you want?    - Nothing. It's nothing.
我沒撒謊，我已經看過你訓練了 你的左拳很厲害
I ain't lying, I've been watching you work. You got a hell of a left.
謝謝你
Thank you.
那你要不要試試？ 看看是不是合適？
So you wanna give this a try? See if it's a fit?
- 噢，當然    - 好
- Yeah, sure.    - Good.
好，因為我覺得你已經夠資格比賽了
Because I think you're ready for a fight.
分開
Break.
我到底做錯了什么，賽利？ 每次我逼近都被她痛擊
What am I doing wrong, Sally? Every time I get inside, she's on me.
你做得很好 你就快把她拖垮了，繼續出拳
You're doing great. You're wearing her down. Keep punching.
- 我不好，我要輸了    - 你就快把她拖垮了
- I ain't doing great, I'm losing.    - You're wearing her down.
沒事吧，親愛的？看得清嗎？
You okay, honey? Can you see okay?
- 加油    - 加油
- Come on.    - Do it.
加油，加油！
Come on, let's do this!
沒錯！
That's it!
今晚真不錯，不是嗎？
Nice night, eh?
老天
Jesus Christ.
那姑娘是羅尼 華盛頓的拳手
That's Lonnie Washington's girl.
非常優秀的拳手
Hell of a fighter.
11場全勝
11-0.
左拳，左拳舉起來
Your left. Keep your left up.
羅尼旗下有很多優秀拳手
Lonnie's got a lot of good fighters.
輕量級冠軍喬伊 阿達喬也在他旗下
He's got Joey Adagio, lightweight champ?
對
Yeah.
你的左拳，該死
Your left, damn it.
要是我肯定不會選她做第一個對手 不過賽利是個好經理人
Wouldn't have been my choice for her first fight, but Sally's a good manager.
- 他一定認為她能打敗她    - 天哪
- He must think she can take her.    - Jesus H.
左拳，左拳舉起來
Your left. Keep your left up.
你認為這么遠的地方她能聽見？
You think she can hear you from back here?
當然，就算麥琪輸了 對賽利也算不了什么
Of course, if Maggie loses, it wouldn't mean anything to Sally.
也許還對他有幫助
Might even help him.
讓羅尼的女選手再勝一場...
Lonnie's girl gets another win...
...羅尼也許會讓賽利的輕量級拳手 去挑戰喬伊 阿達喬的冠軍
...Lonnie might let Sally's lightweight fight Joey Adagio for the title.
賽利想要安排一場和阿達喬的比賽？
Sally's trying to set a fight with Adagio?
嘿，我知道什么？
Hey, what do I know?
我只是來欣賞比賽
I just come because I enjoy the fights.
上帝
Mother of God.
好了，分開
Okay, break.
嘿，過來，過來
Hey. Come here, come here.
嘿，過來
Hey. Get over here.
你老是放低左拳 別再放低左拳了
You're dropping your left hand. Quit dropping your left hand.
嘿，弗蘭基 你能不能讓我跟我的拳手談談？
Hey, Frankie, you mind if I talk to my fighter?
你干得還真不賴啊 你也是這樣指導你的輕量級選手的？
You're doing a hell of a job. Is this the way you advise your lightweight?
我是鄧
Dunn.
- 你在干什么？    - 我在說話，你在干什么？
- What are you doing?    - I'm talking. What are you doing?
- 這是你的拳手么？    - 是我的拳手
- Is this your fighter?    - It's my fighter.
真的不是那么合適，賽利
It ain't fitting real well, Sally.
好吧，你來帶她 反正她也屁都不會打
Fine, you take her. She can't fight worth a shit anyway.
- 誰告訴我到底怎么回事    - 我遲到了，賽利剛才只是替我
- Somebody tell me what's going on.    - I was late. Sally was just subbing for me.
你說她是你的拳手？
You telling me this is your fighter?
對，是我的拳手
Yeah, this is my fighter.
那么你有10秒的時間
Then you got 10 seconds.
我把左手舉起來了 可當我出拳的時候，就總是會放下去
I keep holding my left up, then I throw a punch and it keeps dropping.
- 那就放下去好了    - 那就簡單多了
- Well, let it drop.    - That'd be a lot easier.
她認為她摸透你了
She thinks she knows you.
你左手每次放下 她就從上面打過來
Every time you drop it, she comes right over the top.
那你就等著她，明白嗎？ 她腦子里就這么多東西
So you just wait for her, see? That's all she's thinking about.
- 她收回右拳準備出擊的時--你聽見了嗎?    - 我聽著呢，老板
- When she cocks that right hand... You hear?    - I hear you, boss.
如果她那么做，你就向旁邊躲一步 然后給她一記再見勾拳
When she does, step to the side and come with a good-night hook.
- 能行嗎？    - 看我的吧
- Got one?    - Got it right here.
- 好    - 開始吧，我等著呢
- Okay.    - Fight, or I'm calling it.
- 去教訓她吧    - 拳手的身體了解拳手自己所不了解的東西
- Go give it to her.    - The body knows what fighters don 't.
如何保護自己
How to protect itself.
脖子只能轉動那么多
A neck can only twist so far.
哪怕再多轉一毫米 身體就會說：
Twist it just a hair more, and the body says:
“嘿，還是讓我來吧 因為很明顯你不知道你自己在做什么”
"Hey, I'll take it from here because you obviously don't know what you're doing."
到中立區去
Neutral corner.
- 看見她怎么出拳了么？    - 嗯
- See the way she did that?    - Yeah.
舒格 雷就會這么做 這女人好象他一樣
Sugar Ray would do that. Girl's got sugar.
“躺下，休息 等你恢復知覺我們再談”
"Lie down, now, rest, and we'll talk about this when you regain your senses."
這個叫做擊倒心理
It's called the knockout mechanism.
現在放松一點 你干得不錯
Don't get all carried away, now. You did good.
謝了，老板
Thanks, boss.
你....你忘了規矩
You... You forgot the rule.
- 告訴我規矩是什么？    - 左手要抬起？
- Now, what is the rule?    - Keep my left up?
規矩是要隨時保護自己
It's to protect yourself at all times.
好，規矩是什么？
Now, what is the rule?
- 隨時保護我自己    - 很好，很好
- Protect myself at all times.    - Good, good.
你放棄了我 那對我是什么樣的保護？
You gave me away. How was that protecting me?
那不是保護
It wasn't.
沒關系了
It's okay.
- 我會練習我的左手的，老板    - 把水喝了
- I'll work on my left, boss.    - Drink your water.
除了這一點，我怎么樣？
Other than that, how'd I do?
很好，你做得很好
Fine. You did fine.
你還會再放棄我么？
You gonna leave me again?
永遠不會
Never.
你工作的那個地方 有沒有手工制檸檬酥皮派？
That place you work, do they have homemade lemon meringue pie there?
- 當然有    - 不是罐裝餡料的那種垃圾
- Sure.    - Not the kind with the canned-filling crap?
噢，是很大罐的那種 標簽上寫著“手工制作”
Oh, big can, yay size. Says "homemade" on the label.
- 我想你這個周末休息一下    - 這才星期四
- I want you to take the weekend off.    - It's only Thursday.
- 你打算要和我爭？    - 我知道最好不要有這個想法，老板
- You gonna argue with me?    - Know better than to do that, boss.
嗯，很好
Well, good.
某種角度來看，拳手大都很頑固
All fighters are pigheaded some way or other.
他們的某個部分總覺得 在某件事情上自己比別人知道的更多
Some part of them always thinks they know better than you about something.
你能不能花幾分鐘講講圣母懷胎？
Can you spare a few minutes for the Immaculate Conception?
實際上，就算他們錯了...
Truth is, even if they're wrong...
...就算有那么件事情 可以把他們都毀了...
...even if that one thing is gonna be the ruin of them...
...如果你能把他們徹底打敗 那他們就不算是拳手了
...if you can beat that last bit out of them, then they ain 't fighters at all.
- 我記得我說過讓你周一再來    - 沒錯，老板
- Thought I said I'd see you Monday.    - You sure did, boss.
就是昨晚說的
That was last night.
你說不要和你爭論
You said not to argue with you.
該死的女人總是不按我的指揮做事
Damn woman won't do a thing I tell her.
想聽我的建議么？
You want my advice?
什么？
What?
你的鞋子哪去了？
Where are your shoes?
我給我的腳透透風
I'm airing out my feet.
你的襪子上凈是大洞
You got big holes in your socks.
噢，沒有那么大啦
Oh, they're not that big.
我不是給你錢去買新的了嗎？
Didn't I give you money for some new ones?
這是我的睡襪
These are my sleeping socks.
我的腳晚上需要一些新鮮空氣
My feet like a little air at night.
那你為什么要在白天穿它們？
How come you're wearing them in the daytime, then?
因為我白天穿的襪子上洞太多了
Because my daytime socks got too many holes in them.
那好，如果我多給你些錢 你能去買幾雙新的么？
Well, if I give you some more money, you buy some new socks.
拜托？
Please?
嗯，很有吸引力 不過我不能保證
Well, I'd be tempted, but I couldn't say for sure.
也許會跑到跑道上去
Might find its way to the track.
比賽結束，比賽結束
It's over. It's over.
麥琪沒花多少時間就取得連勝
Didn't take Maggie long to hit her stride.
我解決了呼吸的問題.
I got the breathing thing down.
不，你還是呼吸不正確 因為你第一回合就把對方打倒了
No, you ain't breathing because you're knocking them out in the first round.
- 我還以為那就是重點    - 重點是讓自己變強
- Thought that was the point.    - The point is to get good.
把對方第一回合就擊倒 自己怎么可能進步
Can't get good if you keep knocking them out first round.
我怎么給你再找到對手？
How am I gonna get you fights?
沒人愿意自己的拳手被羞辱
Nobody wants to see their fighter embarrassed, now.
為什么我還要 打這種四回合比賽，老板？
Why am I still doing four-rounders, boss?
因為你的肺還打不了六回合
Because you haven't got the lungs for six rounds.
我一直這么在第一回合 就把她們擊倒就行了
I do if I keep knocking them out in the first round.
弗蘭基讓她又打了場四回合比賽...
Frankie made her fight one more four-rounder...
...只是讓她明白誰說了算數
...just to let her know who was boss.
三，四，五...
Three, four, five...
...六，七....
...six, seven...
抱歉，老板
Sorry, boss.
麥琪對此毫不懷疑
Maggie left no doubt about it.
好了，加油
All right, let's do it.
但是第一場六回合賽并沒那么輕松
Her first six-rounder didn't go quite as smooth.
起來！
Get up!
到你的角落去
To your corner.
- 三，四，五...    - 起來
- Three, four, five...    - Get up.
- ...六，七...    - 起來
...six, seven...    - Get up.
- ...八，九，十，比賽結束    - 你能做到
...eight, nine, ten. It's over.    - You can do this.
麥琪到了第一回合結尾才將對方擊倒
Maggie didn't knock her out till the end of the first round.
在那以后，沒有經理愿意 讓自己的拳手和麥琪交手
After that, no manager wanted to put his fighter in with Maggie.
弗蘭基不得不自己討腰包 來給她安排比賽...
Frankie had to go into his pocket to get her decent fights...
...靠給對方經理人賄賂 來增加對方參賽的興趣
...sweetening the purse by paying managers on the side.
這并沒能持續太久
That only worked for so long.
然后弗蘭基做了他不愿意做的事
Then Frankie did something he hated doing.
他冒了次險
He took a chance.
開始
Box.
他把她晉升了一個級別
He moved her up in class.
這差點成為一個錯誤
That could've been a mistake.
注意右邊！
Watch the right!
注意，注意
Watch it. Watch it.
分開，分開，后退，時間到
Break, break. Step back. Break. Time.
該死，該死，該死
Damn, damn, damn.
給我們兩秒鐘，好嗎？
Give us two seconds, will you?
- 好    - 兩秒鐘就好
- Okay.    - Just two seconds.
- 你的鼻梁骨斷了    - 噢，該死
- Your nose is broke.    - Oh, damn.
- 弄好它    - 我沒辦法，我沒辦法
- Fix it.    - I can't, I can't.
- 你可以的    - 我不行，我準備棄權了
- You can fix it.    - I can't. I've gotta call it.
我見你做過，弄好它
I've seen what you can do. Fix it.
我能把它按回去 但是我不能給你止血
I can snap it back into place, but I can't stop the bleeding.
醫務裁判會中止比賽的
The ring doctor's gonna call it.
求你，弗蘭基，你要是能幫我止血 我就能打倒她
Please, Frankie, if you can stop the blood, I can beat her.
咬住這個
Bite down on this.
- 吸氣    - 什么？
- Inhale.    - What?
- 吸氣    - 什么
吸氣
Breathe in.
- 可以？    - 嗯，沒問題
- Okay, huh?    - Yeah, it's okay.
好，這個變成噴泉之前你有20秒鐘...
All right, you got 20 seconds before this turns into a geyser...
...血會噴到整個前排座位上的
...and it's gonna spray all over the front row.
你只有20秒
Twenty seconds, that's all you've got.
去吧
Now get going.
回到你的角落去
Go to your corner.
三，四，五...
Three, four, five...
- 加油，呼吸，呼吸    - ...六，七，八...
- Come on, breathe. Breathe. ...six, seven, eight...
...九，十
...nine, ten.
“莫 庫什勒”
Mo cuishle.
- 好！    - 太棒了！
- All right!    - Yeah!
對
Right.
你在讀什么
What you reading?
她說什么？
What's she saying?
想知道你在讀什么
Wants to know what you're reading.
是葉芝的作品（愛爾蘭著名詩人） 仰著點頭
It's Yeats. Keep your head back.
你為什么不跟她說說葉芝呢？
Why don't you talk a little Yeats to her.
告訴她那是怎樣一件樂事
Show her what a treat that is.
他媽的什么時候才能輪到她？
When the hell they gonna get to her?
我很好，弗蘭基
I'm okay, Frankie.
- 你今天學到了什么？    - 隨時保護自己
- What'd you learn tonight?    - Always protect myself.
- 規矩是什么？    - 隨時保護自己
- What's the rule?    - Always protect myself.
- 麥琪 菲斯杰拉德?    - 在這里
- Margaret Fitzgerald?    - Here.
我就在這兒等你
I'll be right here.
- 你怎么樣？    - 我？
- How you doing?    - Me?
- 對，你    - 我又沒有受傷
- Yeah, you.    - I'm not the one who's hurt.
鼻子斷了并不是那么受傷
Broken nose don't hurt that much.
為什么你要告訴我這個？
Why are you telling me that?
沒有原因
No reason.
可有些傷太深了 或是離骨頭太近
But some wounds are too deep or too close to the bone.
不管你如何努力，都不能止血
And no matter how hard you work at it, you just can't stop the bleeding.
- 你給你女兒寫信了么？    - 每周都寫
- Did you write your daughter?    - Every week.
我真不明白你為什么要來教堂
I've no idea why you come to church.
在連續十二場比賽擊倒對手勝出后 弗蘭基得到幾個非常不錯的邀請
After her 12th straight knockout, Frankie got a couple of real good offers.
第一個邀請是和 “蘭熊”比麗 奧斯特曼...
The first was to fight Billie "The Blue Bear" Osterman...
...爭奪WBA次中量級頭銜
...for the WBA welterweight title.
“蘭熊”比麗
Billie "The Blue Bear."
比麗原來是東柏林的妓女
Billie was a former prostitute out of East Berlin.
她是這個級別里 手法最骯臟的拳手，臭名遠揚
Had a reputation for being the dirtiest fighter in the ranks.
她看起來一點也不在乎...
Didn't seem to matter to her...
...這樣的動作可能會致人于死地
...that something like that could kill a person.
觀眾喜歡她
And the crowds loved her.
他沒告訴她就把這場比賽拒絕了.
He turned it down without even telling her.
下一個邀請是去挑戰英國冠軍
The next was to fight the British champ...
- 一個剛被比麗擊敗的牙買加女孩    - 喂？
- ...a Jamaican girl Billie just beat.    - Hello?
不感興趣
Not interested.
他也沒接受那個邀請
He turned that down too.
可是很大一筆錢哪，老板
That's a lot of money, boss.
是啊，你掙錢了 為什么還在這里工作？
Yeah, you're making money. What are you still working here for?
那是冠軍賽，對吧？
It's a title match, right?
你是英國人么？ 那個冠軍你拿不走的
Are you British? It's a title you can't take away.
她沒什么好輸的 你也沒什么好贏的
She's got nothing to lose, you got nothing to win.
很可能仍然是一場不錯的比賽呢
Might still be a good fight.
是啊，我剛把你升上次中量級
Yeah, I just... I just brought you up to welterweight.
能和跟你水平相當的選手打就不錯了 還想他媽去挑戰那些冠軍？
Too good to fight these contenders, you'd rather fight some bullshit champ?
我沒發現有和我水平相當的選手啊
Didn't notice I was fighting any contenders.
如果你想的話 隨時可以換經理
Well, you can get yourself another manager any time you want.
實際上，如果你有能力 把自己的臉保護得好一點的話...
In fact, if you'd learn to protect your face a little better...
...我才不會拒絕這筆錢呢
...I wouldn't have to turn down this money.
我的臉暴露出那么多 可還沒被擊倒過，真是個奇跡
My face is out there so much it's a miracle I haven't been knocked out yet.
你今晚不要繼續訓練了
No, you can't work here anymore tonight.
我定了位子
I made us a reservation.
你去洗個澡吧
You might wanna shower.
你的
Here you go.
這是什么？
What's this?
你想要的東西 這不是什么秘密
Well, it ain't no big secret what you're wishing for.
把蠟燭吹了
Go on and blow.
謝謝你
Thank you.
33歲不算大的
Thirty-three ain't so old.
我39歲的時候還在參賽
I was still fighting at 39.
我打了23年
Fought for 23 years.
最近怎么樣，斯科雷普
How's it going, Scrap?
不錯，米奇
Doing good, Mickey.
不錯
Doing good.
- 你要什么？    - 咖啡
- What'll you have?    - Coffee.
你們兩個不講話？
You two not speaking?
不太認識他
Don't hardly know him.
我在37歲生日之后遇到了弗蘭基
I met Frankie right after my 37th birthday.
那時他干的工作是給拳手包扎傷口
He was picking up cut work.
我認為不可能的時候 他總能給我包扎好
He used to patch me up when I thought it was impossible.
有他在賽場邊真不錯
Good man to have in your corner.
是啊
Yes, he is.
我最后一次比賽，在圣伯蒂諾 他也陪了我全場
He stayed with me through my last fight in San Berdu.
我的經理喝醉了，不知所蹤
My manager was off getting drunk somewhere...
只有我和弗蘭基
...and it was just Frankie and me.
我被打得暈頭轉向
I was taking a hellacious beating.
每個人最多能參加多少比賽 都有個數字
Everybody's got a particular number of fights in him.
沒人告訴你那個數字是多少
Nobody tells you what that number is.
我的是109場
Mine was 109.
我只是不愿承認
I just didn't want to admit it.
第四回合
Fourth round, this...
這里被打開了口子
...cut opens up.
鮮血擁進我的眼睛里
Blood starts pouring into my eye.
他們本應該終止那場比賽的 但是，媽的，我是個在圣伯蒂諾的黑人
They should've stopped the fight, but, hell, I was a black man in San Berdu.
我到那里就是去流血的
Blood was what I was there for.
一回合接著一回合 我不斷地讓弗蘭基給我包扎
Round after round, I kept getting Frankie to patch me up.
他想扔毛巾認輸...
He's talking about throwing in the towel...
...但他不是我的經理人 什么也不能扔
...but he ain't my manager, he can't throw in nothing.
一回合接著一回合...
Round after round...
...他一直跟我爭吵
...he's arguing with me.
我幾乎是在笑他，因為，媽的 好象是打在他身上似的
And I'm almost laughing because, hell, it's getting more to him than to me.
我打了15回合
I go 15 rounds...
裁判判我輸了
...Iose by decision.
第二天早上，我的眼睛沒了
Next morning, I lose the eye.
23年來，他從來沒說起過這件事
In 23 years, he's never said a thing about it.
沒這個必要 每次他看我，我都能從他的臉上讀出來
Doesn't have to. I can see it in his face every time he looks at me.
某種程度上
Somehow...
弗蘭基認為自己應該終止那場比賽
...Frankie thinks he should've stopped that fight...
可以挽救我的眼睛
...should've saved my eye.
他一生都希望能收回那第109場比賽
Spends his life wishing he could take back that 109th fight.
但我卻想參加第110場
I wanted to go to 110.
重點是
Thing is...
如果你想取得冠軍
...if you wanna get to the title...
也許他并不是最好人選
...maybe he's not the one to take you there.
你告訴了麥克先生我們今晚會來這里？
You tell Mr.Mack we'd be here tonight?
繼續吃你的蛋糕吧
You go on, eat your cupcake.
不用了，我來吧
No, I got it.
這就是規矩
It's the rule.
隨時保護自己
Always protect yourself.
人們從不采納自己的意見
People never take their own advice.
如果她要離開弗蘭基 最好當時就做
If she was gonna leave Frankie, better she did it to him then.
米奇 麥克先生？
Mr.Mickey Mack?
我是麥琪 菲斯杰拉德
I'm Maggie Fitzgerald.
我聽說你是非常好的經理人 給大個子威利做的很不錯
I hear you're a real good manager, doing good things for Big Willie.
但我想你該知道 我是不會離開鄧先生的
But I thought you should know I ain't never leaving Mr.Dunn...
所以你不需要再找借口好遇見我了
...so you don't need to make any more excuses to bump into me.
不好意思打攪你吃飯了
Sorry for interrupting your dinner.
麥琪總是喜歡剛一交手 就把對手擊倒
Maggie always did like taking them out in the first round.
寄出的信總是原樣退回:
The letters always came back marked the same way:
上面寫著“退還發件人”
"Return to sender."
我給你準備點咖啡
I'll make you some coffee.
你打算拿你的錢干些什么？
What are you doing with your money?
- 存起來    - 好孩子
- Saving it.    - Good girl.
你知道，如果存夠了就可以買座小房
You know, you save enough of it, you ought to get yourself a little house.
現金，不用貸款
Cash, no mortgage.
那還要存一段時間
Gonna be a while before I can do that.
是啊，可能還有一段時間...
Yeah, well, it might be a stretch...
...但你得給自己弄個窩
...but you gotta get yourself a place of your own.
把錢浪費在無關緊要的東西上 你能得到什么？
Go around wasting it on things that don't matter and what do you got?
明白么？
You understand?
很快，如果你等得太久 你什么也得不到
Pretty soon, you wait long enough, you got nothing.
好吧，只要我存夠錢
Okay, soon as I get the money.
我這一生中犯了很多錯誤 我只是不想你走一樣的路
I made a lot of mistakes in my life. I'm just trying to keep you from doing the same.
知道了，老板
I know, boss.
- 我不會長命百歲的    - 這是什么？
- I'm not gonna live forever.    - What is it?
一盒關于你那個英國對手的錄像帶
It's a tape on that girl in England you're gonna fight.
如果你想去爭奪冠軍 我們得做-- 嘿！
If you're gonna go for the title, we got some moves to... Hey.
嘿，快他媽下來 知道我有多大歲數么？
Hey, get the hell down. You know how old I am?
- 謝謝老板，非常感謝    - 嗯
- Thank you, boss. Thank you so much.    - Yeah.
不用謝，親愛的 給，把--我把這個放到機器里去
You're welcome, darling. Here, just... Here, let me put this in the machine.
什么機器？
What machine?
你沒有電視，是么？
Don't have a TV, huh?
沒有
No.
耶！
Yeah!
好了，好的
All right. Okay.
- 還有十分鐘，親愛的    - 謝謝
- Ten minutes, love.    - Thank you.
那家伙說他愛我
Man says he loves me.
他不可能是第一個這么說的男人
He's probably not the first one to say that.
除了我爸以外的第一個
First since my daddy.
我要是贏了，你說他會向我求婚么？
I win, you think he'll propose?
你贏了，我就向你求婚
You win, I'll propose.
看，我給你帶了件禮物
Look, I got you a gift here.
我想這是其他人的吧
I think they gave you somebody else's.
不，不，就是這個
No, no, this is it.
“莫 庫什勒”是什么意思？
What's it mean?
不知道，是高盧語
I don't know. Just something in Gaelic.
- 真漂亮    - 嗯，我也這么認為
- It's beautiful.    - Yeah, I thought so.
- 是啊    - 真絲的
- Yeah.    - Real silk thread.
來自美國的挑戰者...
From the United States of America, the challenger...
...麥琪 菲斯杰拉德
...Maggie Fitzgerald.
“莫 庫什勒” 你看到她袍子上的字了嗎？
Mo cuishle. Did you see what was on her robe?
- “莫 庫什勒”，“莫 庫什勒”    - “莫 庫什勒”
- Mo cuishle. Mo cuishle.    - Mo cuishle.
她本不是本晚的賣點
She wasn 't the main attraction.
她的比賽是一場中量級拳王賽的墊場賽
She was on the undercard of a middleweight title fight.
但如果你問問在場的人...
But ask someone who was there...
...他們都不記得 當晚參加比賽的其他選手了
...they couldn 't tell you who else fought that night.
開始
Box.
- 加油！    -“莫 庫什勒”！
- Come on!    - Mo cuishle!
“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
“莫 庫什勒”！
Mo cuishle!
“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
她很強
She's tough.
我無法靠近 我無法靠近打到她
I can't get inside. I can't get close enough to hit her.
- 你知道為什么嗎？    - 為什么？
- You know why that is?    - Why?
因為她是個比你更好的拳手
She's a better fighter than you are.
她更年輕，更強壯 更有經驗
She's younger, she's stronger, and she's more experienced. Now...
現在你打算怎么辦？
...what are you gonna do about it?
去吧
Get in there.
開始
Box.
三，四，五，六..
Three, four, five, six...
...七，八，九，十
...seven, eight, nine, ten.
“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
- “莫 庫什勒”！    - “莫 庫什勒”！
- Mo cuishle!    - Mo cuishle!
你知道我可以問其他人，對嗎？
I could ask someone, you know?
好啊
Good.
你知道以后告訴我
You find out, you let me know.
不管那個名字是什么意思 人們記住了
Whatever it meant, the name stuck.
麥琪打遍愛丁堡，巴黎，布魯塞爾 和阿姆斯特丹
Maggie fought in Edinburgh and Paris, Brussels and Amsterdam.
觀眾總是高呼“莫 庫什勒”
It was always mo cuishle.
看起來到處是愛爾蘭人...
Seems there are Irish people everywhere...
...或者是想成為愛爾蘭人的人
...or people who wanna be.
當他們回到美國的時候...
By the time they came back to the States...
...麥琪已經達到了一個新的水平
...Maggie was in a whole new league.
“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
后來他們受到另一場冠軍賽的邀請
After that they got another offer to fight for the title.
怎么分成？
What's the split?
- 六四開    - 好
- Sixty-forty.    - Good.
好，我們六，你們四 因為麥琪是吸引觀眾的籌碼
We'll take 60 and you take 40, being as that Maggie's the draw.
那個小女孩
That little girl?
你真的認為我說的不對？ 你認為觀眾會說...
You think I'm wrong, really? You think people are saying...
...他們想看一個破爛德國人 痛揍無名氏小姐？
...that they wanna see some scabby Kraut beat up on little Miss What's-Her-Name?
你要能找到那樣的人，我們就拿四
You find someone who says that, and we'll take the 40.
給你
There you go.
他們現在是六四開 不過最后會是五五開
They're at 60-40, but they'll come up to 50-50.
那女孩現在怎么樣了？
How's that girl doing?
她腦震蕩了，耳鼓膜破裂
Well, she's got a concussion and a broken eardrum.
她沒事吧
She be all right?
- 她要是有事呢？    - 也許我應該給她送點什么
- And if she isn't?    - Maybe I should send her something.
你愿意的話，把你的獎金寄給她好了 我想她會接受
Well, you could send her your check if you'd like. I'm sure she'd take it.
老板？
Boss?
我們說起過的那座房子？
That little house we talked about?
我買下了
I bought it.
聰明的姑娘
Well, smart girl.
給我媽買的 離她現在住的地方不到一英里
For my mama. It's only about a mile from where she lives now.
如你所言，沒有貸款
No mortgage, just like you said.
你是個好女兒
You're a good daughter.
她還不知道
She don't know about it yet.
我希望我們可以多待一天 開車到那里去
I was hoping maybe we could stay an extra day, drive over there?
我知道她想見你
I know she wants to meet you.
好吧，可以
Yeah, we could do that.
哦，天哪，媽媽快出來
Oh, my God. Mama, come on out here.
麥琪回來了
Mary M's here.
- 這是約翰遜家的舊屋    - 不再是了
- This is the Johnsons' old house.    - Not anymore.
它是你的了，媽媽 還有瑪代爾和孩子們
It's all yours, Mama. For you and Mardell and the kids.
- 麥琪，這房子是你給我買的？    - 對，是你的了，全部付清了
- Mary M, you bought this for me?    - Yeah, all yours, free and clear.
親愛的
Darling...
沒冰箱，也沒爐灶
There's no fridge. No stove neither.
在你們搬進來前，會準備好的
They'll be here before you move in.
- 你花了多少錢？    - 你不用管
- How much money did this cost you?    - Never mind that.
- 你不該這么做    - 您需要一個體面的住處
- You shouldn't have done this.    - You need a decent place.
你不該這么做 你該先問問我的
You shouldn't have done it. You should've asked me first.
如果政府發現了 他們會停掉我的社會福利的
Government's gonna find out about this, they're gonna stop my welfare.
- 媽媽，他們不會的    - 他們會的，你很好，有自己的工作
- Mama, no, they ain't.    - They are. You're fine, you're working...
但沒有福利我活不下去
...but I can't live without my welfare.
媽媽我會給你寄錢的
Mama, I'll send you money.
醫療怎么辦？ 公費醫療會把我從名單上劃掉
What about my medicine? Medicaid gonna cut me off.
- 我拿什么錢買藥啊？    - 我會給你寄更多的錢
- How am I supposed to get my medicine?    - I'll send you more money.
我希望你沒有預期JD要住進來
I hope you don't expect J.D. To move in with us.
你知道他快出獄了
He's getting out, you know.
為什么不把錢直接給我？
Why didn't you just give me the money?
為什么必須給我買房子？
Why'd you have to buy me a house?
不是必須，媽媽，但房子是你的了
I didn't have to, Mama, but it's yours.
如果想要錢，把它賣掉好了
You want the money, sell it.
我不--
I don't...
我知道你不想傷害我們...
I know you didn't mean nothing hurtful...
...只是有時候你沒把事情想清楚
...but sometimes you just don't think things through.
- 這倒是真的，媽媽    - 我會試著不把房子賣掉
- That's true, Mama.    - I'll try and keep the house.
我只是擔心養房子的那些費用
I'm just worried about all those expenses.
我會給你寄更多錢的
I'll send you some more money.
那個人把你打成這樣的？
That man hitting you?
這是比賽留下的
It's from the fight.
我是一名拳擊手，媽媽
I'm a fighter, Mama.
找個老公吧，麥琪
Find a man, Mary M.
過正常的生活
Live proper.
人們知道你的職業后就會嘲笑你
People hear about what you're doing and they laugh.
告訴你我很難過，但是他們嘲笑你
Hurts me to tell you, but they laugh at you.
嗨
Hi.
你養過狗么？
You ever own a dog?
沒有
Nope.
我差點養了一只巴斯頓的中型狗
Closest I ever came was a middleweight from Barstow.
我爸養過一只德國牧羊犬，埃克斯
My daddy had a German shepherd, Axel.
埃克斯的后腿不太好
Axel's hindquarters were so bad...
它得用自己的前腿拖著自己 從一個房間走到另一個房間
...he had to drag himself room to room by his front legs.
看他跑過廚房的地板
Me and Mardell would bust up laughing...
我和瑪代爾都會忍不住大笑
...watching him scoot across the kitchen floor.
爸爸，他當時病的很重 自己都站不起來
Daddy, he was so sick by then, he couldn't hardly stand himself.
但一天早上他起床以后 把埃克斯抱到他的拖車上
But one morning he got up, carried Axel to his rig...
他們倆跑進樹林里 又唱又叫
...and the two of them went off into the woods, singing and howling.
直到那天晚上他獨自回來時
But it wasn't till he got home that night alone that I saw...
我才發現卡車里的鏟子
...the shovel in the back of the truck.
好想再看看他們倆在一起的樣子
Sure miss watching the two of them together.
我現在除了你誰都沒有了，弗蘭基
I got nobody but you, Frankie.
對，你還有我
Well, you've got me.
至少在你找到一個好經理人以前是這樣
At least, that is, until we find you a good manager.
嘿，我們能在這停一下么？
Hey, can we stop just up here?
好
Yeah.
這里有附近最好的檸檬派
This place has the best lemon pie around.
沒有那種惡心的罐裝餡
None of that canned-filling crap.
現在我可以上天堂了
Now I can die and go to heaven.
我以前和爸爸常來這
I used to come here with Daddy.
我不知道象這樣的地方會不會出售
Wonder if a place like this is for sale.
我還有點積蓄
I got a little bit of savings.
（艾記小吃店）
好，好，謝謝
That's fine, fine, thanks.
嘿，丹吉爾到底在看什么？
Hey, what the hell's Danger looking at?
好像是另外一瓶水
Looks like another bottle of water.
想和我們一起到拉斯維加斯去么？
Wanna come to Vegas with us?
看你們在老虎機那兒受罪？ 我的心臟受不了那種刺激
Watch you suffer over the nickel slots? My heart can't take that kind of pounding.
呃，她有場冠軍賽，對手是“蘭熊”
Well, she's got a title shot. The Blue Bear.
百萬美金對半分
Million dollars, split right down the center.
啊，不錯啊，弗蘭基，很不錯
That's good, Frankie. That's real good.
我想找個好助手一起去
Well, I could use a good second.
但是找不到 所以我來問問你
Can't find one, I thought I'd ask you.
哦，我他媽為什么會同意呢？
Now, why the hell would I wanna do that?
因為你是一個 從來沒得過冠軍的半瞎的老傻瓜
Well, because you're a half-blind old fool who never got there himself.
我想你可能想去體驗一下 站在冠軍賽的繩圈里的感覺
I thought you might like to feel what it's like to be in a ring on a title match.
不好意思，我替你遺憾了
Excuse me for feeling sorry for you.
我不去，你還是在拉斯維加斯找吧
No, you pick up somebody there in Vegas.
找個年輕點的
Somebody with young hands.
你不會哭吧？ 我已經帶上一個女孩了
You're not gonna cry now, are you? I've already got one girl.
如果我離開這地方一天...
I leave this place for one day...
...知道回來時這里會變成什么樣么？
...got any idea what it would look like when I come back?
和現在這樣差不多吧
Kind of like it looks right now.
噢，去死吧
Oh, go to hell.
告訴麥琪沒有拳王腰帶不要回來
You tell Maggie don't come back here without a belt.
知道了
Will do.
嘿，斯科雷普先生
Hey, Mr.Scrap.
我有個問題 可是我覺得問出來好傻
I got a question, but I feel real stupid asking it.
在這里沒有問題是愚蠢的，丹吉爾
No such thing as a stupid question there, Danger.
好吧
Okay.
你怎么把冰塊從這么小的口里放進去的？
How'd you get all the ice in here through this little tiny hole?
我一直在想
I've been thinking on it.
但想不出來
Can't figure it out.
我來做給你看吧，丹吉爾
Why don't I show you, Danger.
- 你可以，你可以做給我看？    - 我想可以，我想可以
- You could do that? You could show me?    - I think so. I think so.
還有，斯科雷普先生 我有點覺得我準備好參加比賽了
Also, Mr.Scrap, I was kind of thinking I might be ready for a fight.
我拿了票，你準備好了么？
Well, I got the tickets. You ready?
- 我們坐飛機去？    - 你寧愿開車？
- We're flying?    - Would you rather drive?
你是問我嗎？
You're asking me?
你是想坐飛機還是開車過去？
Would you rather fly, or would you rather drive?
我終于有權決定某些事了么？
So I finally get to decide something?
我說的就是這個意思
That's what I'm saying.
好吧
Fine.
好，飛過去，開車回來
Fly there, drive back.
這是我聽過的最愚蠢的事 我們怎么會那么做？
That's the stupidest thing I've ever heard. How the hell we gonna do that?
你說過讓我決定的
You said it was up to me.
丹吉爾，給他們點顏色
Give them hell there, Danger.
嘿，老家伙，馬桶的水溢出來了
Hey, old school, the toilet's overflowing.
嘿，冒失鬼，過來一下
Hey, Flippy, come here for a minute.
我的天啊
Jesus.
老天爺
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
噢，上帝！
Oh, God!
蠢豬
Dumb-ass.
來呀，丹吉爾 來呀，丹吉爾
Come on, Danger. Come on, Danger.
來呀，防守
Come on. Defense!
本來我可以坐在海市蜃樓酒店里...
Could be sitting up at the Mirage...
...喝著邁泰酒...
...drinking mai tais...
...看著裸體女人
...Iooking at naked women.
來呀，丹吉爾 舉起手來打呀
Come on, Danger, put up your hands and fight.
丹吉爾，出去吧！
Danger, get out of there!
反擊啊，快點
Fight back! Come on!
- 對了，丹吉爾，對了！    - 干得好，哥們兒
- There you go, Danger, there you go!    - Good job, man.
左刺拳打他 來呀
Jab him with the left. Come on.
來呀
Come on.
嘿，來呀，冒失鬼
Hey, come on now, Flip.
- 你在干什么？放開他    - 好了，好了
- What you doing? Let him go.    - All right. Okay.
我扶住你了，來，來
I got you. Come on, come on.
沒事了
It's all right.
我們不需要教練
We don't need no corner trainer.
我怎么樣，斯科雷普先生！
How'd I do, Mr.Scrap?
干得不錯，丹吉爾，相當不錯
You did good, Danger. You did real good.
你是我的英雄，棒極了
You my man. You rock.
哦，冒失鬼，還沒完呢
Come on, Flip, man, you ain't done.
你還沒打出氣勢呢
You ain't even fight good yet.
每個人都可能輸的
Anybody can lose one fight.
每個人都會輸的，年輕人 你會東山再起的
Anybody can lose one, son. You'll come back from this.
你會是世界冠軍的
You'll be champion of the world.
不，我不會的，斯科雷普先生
No, I won't, Mr.Scrap.
我早該知道的
I should have knowed.
- 快點，我們不需要閑扯    - 我來幫你
- Come on. We don't need to be talking.    - Let me help you.
噢，不用，我可以 幫我把尼龍扣解開就行了
Oh, no, I can do her. Just untie the Velcro for me.
好了
All right.
喂，別摘手套啊，哥們兒 你還沒用過呢，丹吉爾
Come on, don't take the gloves off, man. You ain't even used them, Danger.
能借用一下么，丹吉爾？
Mind if I borrow this, Danger?
小子，你是不是叫丹吉爾啊？
Man, I thought your name was Danger.
快起來
Come on, now.
哦，我明白了 我要先打弱智，再打老頭
Oh, oh, I see. Now I get to fight a retard and a old man.
給ESPN電視臺打電話 因為這個東西可是不能言傳啊
Call ESPN, because you can't write this shit.
當心，謝瑞爾 輕點，謝瑞爾
Look out, Shawrelle. Easy, Shawrelle.
繼續，哥們兒
Keep going, man.
好了，兄弟
All right, man.
他也不那么厲害啊
He ain't so tough.
第110場
One hundred and ten.
去找個工作吧，廢物
Get a job, punk.
贏了這場，我就告訴你是什么意思
Win this one, I'll tell you what it means.
我給你找了幾個吹風笛的
I got you some pipers.
“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
“莫 庫什勒”！ “莫 庫什勒”！ “莫 庫什勒”！
上啊
All right, now!
我要你不停擊打她的胸部...
I want you to jab her right in the tits...
...直到它們腫得掉下來為止
...until they turn blue and fall off.
女士們先生們 這一場是今晚的...
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the feature...
...壓軸節目
...presentation of the evening.
這一角是挑戰者 麥琪 菲斯杰拉德...
In this corner, the challenger, Maggie Fitzgerald...
...紅角選手
...in the red corner.
在藍角的是...
In the blue corner...
...WBA次中量級世界冠軍...
...the WBA welterweight champion of the world...
...“藍熊”比麗
...Billie "The Blue Bear."
上帝啊
Sweet Jesus.
菲斯杰拉德把藍熊逼到繩圈的外圍 她一上來的氣勢很猛
Fitzgerald is pushing The Blue Bear around the ring. She's coming on strong.
挑戰者快步移動 用組合拳向頭部和軀干攻擊
Challenger darts in, lands a combination to the head and the body.
- 一個右勾拳打中了冠軍    - 好的
- And a right hook stuns the champ.    - All right.
分開！
Break it up!
分開！分開！
Break it! Break it!
再這么干的話，就扣你一分 明白了嗎？
Do that one more time, it'll cost you a point, do you hear me?
去打吧
Go fight.
你他媽的混蛋
You motherfucker.
靠，這他媽算什么？
Come on. What the fuck?
好了，不能再這樣了 我要扣你一分
All right, that's it. I'm gonna take away a point.
藍角選手扣一分
One point deduction off the blue corner.
--反擊了，打中了菲斯杰拉德....
- Comes back, hits Fitzgerald...
裁判，眼睛睜大點，你....
Ref, open your eyes, you...
女士們先生們 冠軍賽的第一回合結束了
Ladies and gentlemen, the first round is in the books on this championship match.
- 拿住    - 好的
- Hold onto that.    - There you go.
- 看起來不錯    - 你再使那種陰招...
- Looking good.    - You pull that crap one more time...
...我就取消你的比賽資格
...you're disqualified.
沒事的
It's gonna be all right.
毫不懷疑，老板
Got no doubt, boss.
好，照看好你自己
Okay, just watch yourself.
離這位夫人遠點
Stay away from this dame.
去中立角，中立角
Go to the neutral corner. Neutral corner.
- 四，五，六...    - 趴著吧，你個婊子
- Four, five, six...    - Stay down, you bitch.
...七，八，九
...seven, eight, nine.
好啊，好啊！
Yeah, yeah!
分開，分開
Break it! Break it!
菲斯杰拉德連續擊打藍熊 東德的冠軍....
Fitzgerald continues to pummel The Blue Bear. The East German champion...
好！加油！
Yes! Come on!
我來，我來！
I got it! I got it.
眼睛有點模糊，老板
Eyes are blurring, boss.
- 你需要幾只眼完成比賽？    - 一只足夠了
- How many eyes you need to finish this?    - One's enough.
- 好    - 那么...
- Good.    - Now...
...我怎么對付這只熊？
...what do I do about the Bear?
你知道繞到外側 擊打肝臟部位的套路嗎？
Do you know that step into the outside and hook into the liver?
- 我一直都這么打的，可她是銅頭鐵臂    - 我不要你打肝臟的部位
- I been doing that. She's made of steel.    - I don't want you to go to the liver.
我要你照準 她的小屁股下面打，明白嗎？
I want you to hit her right up under her skinny ass, understand?
照準坐骨神經打 不停的打那個部位
Right in the sciatic nerve. Just keep digging it in there.
而且要一直纏著她 你聽到了么？
And just keep sticking her. You hear that?
- 裁判員怎么辦？    - 站在裁判和“熊”的中間...
- What about the ref?    - Keep between the ref and the Bear...
...就沒問題了
...and everything will just be fine.
比賽是你的，提高警惕
This is yours. You keep your guard up.
保持注意力
You keep it up.
噢，好啊！
Oh, yeah!
分開，分開！
Break, break!
“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！“莫 庫什勒”！
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
醫生
Doctor.
來呀
Come on.
呼吸
Breathe.
很好，呼吸
That's it. Breathe.
很好
Good.
看著我，注意看我
Look at me. Concentrate on me.
呼吸
Breathe.
很好
Good.
就這樣
That's it.
呼吸
Breathe.
親愛的，感覺怎樣？
How you feeling, darling?
留胡子啦，老板
Growing a beard, boss?
我想可能會增加我的女人緣
I thought it might help me with the ladies.
很難說哦
Can't say it does.
會不--會不會很疼？
Does it...? Does it hurt much?
一點也不
Don't hurt at all.
那很好
Well, that's good.
弗蘭基呢？
Where's Frankie?
他在....
Well, he's...
他在外面和醫生談
He's out there talking to the doctors.
可能在教他們怎樣做好本職工作
Probably telling them how to do their job.
他們在告訴他 我是C1和C2頸椎完全損傷
They're telling him I'm a C1 and C2 complete.
就是說我的脊椎斷得很徹底 完全沒法修復了
Means that my spinal cord's so broke they'll never be able to fix it.
我下半生都得這么躺著
Gonna be frozen like this the rest of my life.
我叫他們告訴他 我不知道他能不能接受的了
I asked them to tell him. I don't know how he's gonna take it.
你看了比賽么？
Did you see the fight?
當然
Of course I did.
你完全壓倒了她，麥琪
You had her cold, Maggie.
我不應該把手放下去的
I shouldn't have dropped my hands.
我不該轉身的
I shouldn't have turned.
隨時保護我自己
Always protect myself.
這句話他和我說了多少遍了
How many times he tell me that?
是啊...
Yeah...
...他說話總是喜歡一遍遍重復
...he does like to repeat himself.
你能告訴他我很抱歉嗎？
Will you tell him I'm real sorry?
不能
No.
不，我不會這么做的，麥琪
I won't do no such thing, Maggie.
真是該死啊
Damnedest thing.
你有什么計劃？
So, what's the plan?
我知道你已經計劃好了 你還是告訴我的好
I know you got one, so you might as well tell me what it is.
是你的錯
It's your fault.
對，她現在那樣躺著 都是你的錯
Yeah, it's your fault she's lying in there like that.
你纏著我讓我訓練她
You kept after me until I trained her.
我知道我不該這么做的 她再怎么說也是個女孩
I knew I shouldn't have done it, her being a girl and all.
其他的一切也不斷向我顯示 不要訓練她
Everything kept telling me not to.
除了你
Everything but you.
我要把你從這兒弄出去
I'm gonna get you out of here.
這里的醫生屁都不懂
These doctors around here don't know squat.
要不然他們為什么要在沙漠里住著？
Otherwise, why would they be living out here in the desert?
一旦你能被移動了...
As soon as you're able to be moved...
...我會找個地方 有人真正學過醫的地方
...we'll find some place where they've actually studied medicine.
你就在那里修養好了，我會....
You just rest there, I'II...
我正在辦
I'm on it.
弗蘭基肯定打遍了全美國醫院的電話...
Frankie must have called every hospital in America...
...尋找能告訴他 她可以被治好的人
...Iooking for somebody who'd tell him they could fix her.
有兩次很接近成功 可他們給她做了徹底檢查后...
He came close twice, till they checked her over...
...也表示無能為力
...said there was nothing to be done.
兩個月后 她病情穩定到可以被移動了
Took two months till she was stable enough to move.
他們有護士專門做這個，你知道的
They got nurses for that, you know.
嗯，可她們太業余了
Yeah, but they're amateurs.
因為不能移動，她長了褥瘡
She developed skin ulcers because she couldn't change positions.
謝謝你
Thank you.
他們坐著救護車 完成了六個小時的旅程
They made the six-hour trip by ambulance.
飛過去，開車回來
Fly there, drive back.
弗蘭基找到的康復中心 是個不錯的地方
The rehab center Frankie found was a nice place.
他們把麥琪照顧地很周到
They took good care of Maggie.
即使他們沒有的話 她也不會抱怨什么
She wouldn 't have complained if they hadn 't.
每天要花幾小時才能讓她上輪椅
Took several hours every day to get her ready for the wheelchair.
一，二，三，起
One, two, three, up.
由于她無法自主呼吸
Since she couldn't breathe on her own...
呼吸器總是開著
...her respirators were always on.
氧氣24小時不間斷地 被輸進她的身體里
Oxygen was pumped into her 24 hours a day.
麥琪的媽媽打電話來說 他們會來看她
Maggie's mama called to say they were all coming for a visit.
在接下來的兩周里 她每天都在窗前等他們
She waited by the window every day for the next two weeks.
當然
Sure.
弗蘭基最后終于追蹤到了他們
Frankie finally tracked them down.
發現他們六天前就住進旅館了
Learned they'd checked into their hotel six days earlier.
弗蘭基一直給他們留言 但總沒有回音
Kept leaving messages which were never returned.
你不用整天都待在這兒
You don't have to hang around all day.
我喜歡這里，沒關系的
I like it here. I don't mind.
其實就算你不在，我也會來讀書的
In fact, if you weren't here, I'd come here anyway to read my books.
媽媽馬上會來分擔一些負擔的
Mama will be here soon to share some of the burden.
哦，這不是什么負擔
Well, it's no burden.
給
Here.
讀讀這個
Read this.
好了，好了，行了
Okay, okay, that's enough.
讀得太糟糕了
That's terrible.
我給你翻成英文吧
Anyway, I'll tell you in English what you were saying.
上面說：
It says:
“我要起身去了，去往那茵湖島”
I will arise and go now And go to Innisfree
“用泥土和樹枝，蓋上一間小木房”
And a small cabin build there Of clay and wattles made
“我享受著彼方的寧靜，它緩緩滴零”
And I shall have some peace there For peace comes dropping slow
“從晨曦的面紗，到蟋蟀歌唱的地方”
Dropping from the veils of the morning To where the cricket sings.
還不賴，對吧？
Not bad, huh?
你要蓋一間小木屋么，老板？
You gonna build a cabin, boss?
- 我？    - 對
- Me?    - Yeah.
你知道，等你收山之后
You know, when you quit all this.
你是說拳擊？
You mean boxing?
不，我永遠不會收山的
No, I'll never quit.
我太喜歡那汗臭味道了，我想
I like the stink too much, I guess.
你想？我看你邊看書...
You think? Because I could see you there real easy...
...邊吃檸檬派很愜意呀
...with your books and lemon pie.
你呢？想在小木屋里生活么？
How about you? Would you like to go live in a cabin?
我可以學怎么烤東西
I could learn how to bake.
那樣的話，我....
Well, then, I'II...
我也許要開始找了
Maybe I'll start looking then.
是啊
Yeah.
- 去吧    - 好的，聽起來不錯
- Go ahead.    - All right. Okay, sounds good.
嘿，我是弗蘭基 鄧 我們在密蘇里見過
Hi, I'm Frankie Dunn. I met you back out in Missouri.
我女兒在哪？
Where's my little girl?
你們不應該回旅館換身衣服再來嗎？
Don't you think you ought to go back to the hotel and change?
她還不知道你們已經來了一周 忙著拜訪米老鼠呢
She doesn't know you've been here a week visiting Woody and Mickey.
我們和我妹妹有正事談 你干嗎不干脆告訴我們她在哪呢？
We got business with my sister. Why don't you just tell us where she is.
你肯定是JD 那你肯定是那個談正經事的家伙？
Oh, you must be J.D. And you must be the business guy?
你們錯過了一些東西
There's some rides you missed.
你們不如回去 我來告訴她你們來不成了
Why don't you go back. I'll tell her you couldn't make it.
我開了這么遠的路來照顧孩子
I drove all the way here to take care of my child.
你卻暗示我不是個好母親？
And you're suggesting I'm not a good mother?
麥琪哪里都去不了
Mary M. Can't go nowhere.
否則我們早帶她去逛迪斯尼樂園了
If we could've taken her to Disneyland, we would've.
麥琪 菲斯杰拉德?
Margaret Fitzgerald?
就在這里，301房間
Right down here, 301.
- 快來，媽媽    - 我們走
- Come on, Mama.    - Let's go.
后來我看到自己呼吸
And I saw myself breathing.
我的身體上下起伏
Like, my body was going up and down.
我想，“為什么沒人告訴我？”
I thought, "Why didn't somebody tell me?"
你的頭發得洗了 有點太油了
Your hair needs washing. It's kind of greasy.
只是些....
It's just a...
只是些法律上的程序
It's just some kind of legal thing.
是什么？
What is it?
你們談得怎樣了？
How we all doing here?
不好意思，親愛的 我們時間不多
Sorry, darling, but we ain't got a lot of time.
約翰遜先生收了我們一大筆錢 來保證這件事不出紕漏
Mr.Johnson's charging us a lot of money to be here to make sure this is done proper.
你們不如把那個留下 我等會兒讀給她聽
Why don't you just leave that. I'll read it to her later.
嘿，老家伙
Hey, old man...
你是我們家人么？
...you part of our family?
別管閑事
Stay the hell out of this.
念給我聽，媽媽
Read it to me, Mama.
只是些法律程序 用來保護你的錢的
Well, it's just something legal to protect your money.
媽媽你不用擔心
Mama, you don't have to worry.
拳擊協會會支付這里所有的費用的
The boxing commission's paying for all this, everything.
如果不呢，麥琪？
But what if they don't, Mary M?
約翰遜先生說他們可以收走我的房子
Mr.Johnson says they can take my house.
如果你把財產轉移給你母親 那就沒人能動得了了
If you assign your assets to your mother, no one can touch them.
不用管醫生，喪葬費什么的
No doctors, no funeral expenses.
- 什么都不用理會了    - 你看，不如你們把這個留下
- Nothing.    - Yeah, look, why don't you just leave it.
- 我以后再讀給她--    - 無意冒犯，這不關你的事
- Then I'll just read it to her later on...    - With respect, this ain't your business.
好吧，我在走廊里等
All right. I'll be out in the hall.
你一直是個好女兒，麥琪
You been a good daughter, Mary M.
你簽了這份文件
You sign that paper...
就能照顧你一家
...it'll take care of your family...
正如你父親所愿
...the way your daddy would've wanted you to.
嗯，你怎么簽字呢？
How do you make your mark?
能拿住筆么？
Can you hold a pen?
她只能用牙齒，媽媽
She gotta do it with her teeth, Mama.
你得把筆放到她嘴里去
You gotta put it in her mouth.
好了，親愛的
Here you go, honey.
你看了那場比賽么，媽媽？
Did you see the fight, Mama?
親愛的 你知道我對那東西是什么感覺
Honey, you know how I feel about that.
我打得不錯
I did pretty good.
你輸了，麥琪
You lost, Mary M.
聽說不是你的錯，但你輸了
Ain't your fault, the way I heard it, but you lost.
不能把你現在剩下的東西也輸掉
Don't wanna lose the rest of what you got left.
對了
There you go.
你怎么了？
What happened to you?
這是什么意思？
Well, what's that supposed to mean?
媽媽，你帶上瑪代爾和JD回家吧
Mama, you take Mardell and J.D. And get home.
別等我告訴律師 你擔心領不到社會福利...
Before I tell that lawyer that you were so worried about your welfare...
...所以根本就沒按規定 簽那些房產的證明
...you never signed those house papers like you were supposed to.
所以只要我愿意 我可以把房子賣了...
So any time I feel like it, I can sell that house...
...不用理你這個又肥又懶的鄉巴佬
...from under your fat, lazy, hillbilly asses.
如果你敢再來，我就那么做
And if you ever come back, that's exactly what I'll do.
也許應該有人數點到10
Well, maybe someone ought to count to 10.
不是很好聞吧，醫生？
Don't smell real pretty, does it, doc?
可能保不住了，麥琪
We might have to lose it, Maggie.
他們拿掉了我的腿，老板
They took my leg, boss.
不會有事的，聽到嗎？
It's gonna be all right, you hear?
我總能聽到你的聲音，老板
I always hear your voice, boss.
需要什么嗎？
You need anything?
我想知道“莫 庫什勒”的意思
I need to know what "mo cuishle" means.
可是你沒有贏啊
But you didn't win.
我不用告訴你的
I don't have to tell you.
你是我見過的最壞的人
You're the meanest man I ever met.
難怪沒有人愛你
No wonder no one loves you.
你讓我想起了我父親
You remind me of my daddy.
他肯定是個...
Well, he must have been...
...非常聰明，英俊的人
...a very intelligent, handsome man.
你不會再讓我讀葉芝了，對吧？
You ain't gonna make me talk no more Yeats, are you?
不，我...
No, I was...
...正在看城市大學的宣傳材料
...Iooking at this catalog from City College.
我想給你弄個輪椅...
I thought I'd get you a wheelchair...
...可以用吸管控制的那種
...maybe the kind that operates by blowing through a straw.
我想你可能想去上學
I thought maybe you'd like to go back to school.
求你幫個忙，老板
I got a favor to ask you, boss.
沒問題
Sure.
什么事都行
Anything you want.
記得我爸是怎么幫埃克斯的么？
Remember what my daddy did for Axel?
想都不要想
Don't even think about that.
我不能象現在這樣，弗蘭基
I can't be like this, Frankie.
在我已經成就那么多以后
Not after what I done.
我見識了整個世界
I seen the world.
人們高呼我的名字
People chanted my name.
喔...
Well...
...不是我的本名 是你給我起的該死的名字
...not my name, some damn name you gave me.
可他們為我歡呼
But they were chanting for me.
我上過雜志
I was in magazines.
你以為我以前做過這樣的夢么？
You think I ever dreamed that'd happen?
我生出來的時候只有2磅1.5盎司
I was born at 2 pounds, 1 and a half ounces.
爸爸以前總說我是打拼 到這個世界上的...
Daddy used to tell me I fought to get into this world...
...我也會打出一片天地
...and I'd fight my way out.
那是我唯一想做的，弗蘭基
That's all I wanna do, Frankie.
我只是不想為那個和你打
I just don't wanna fight you to do it.
我得到了我要的
I got what I needed.
全部都得到了
I got it all.
別讓他們從我身邊一點點地拿走
Don't let them keep taking it away from me.
別讓我一直躺在這 直到聽不見人們的歡呼聲為止
Don't let me lie here till I can't hear those people chanting no more.
我不能
I can't.
求求你
Please.
拜托，不要求我
Please, don't ask me.
我在求呢
I'm asking.
我不能
I can't.
喂？
Hello?
午夜時分...
In the middle of the night...
...麥琪自己找到了辦法
...Maggie had found her own solution.
她咬舌了
She had bit her tongue.
停下來，停下來
Stop. Stop.
看著我，看著我
Look at me. Look at me.
差點失血過多而死 直到他們把她的傷口縫合
Nearly bled to death before they stitched her up.
在弗蘭基到來以前，她恢復了知覺 把縫上的傷口又撕開了
She came around and ripped them out before Frankie even got there.
他們又把傷口縫起來
They stitched her up again...
墊起了舌頭 以免她再咬舌自盡
...padded the tongue so she couldn't bite.
你不能那么做，你知道的
You can't do it, you know that.
我知道，神父
I do, Father.
可你不知道她有多遲鈍
But you don't know how thick she is...
訓練她有多難
...how hard it was to train her.
其他拳手你叫他們做什么 他們就做什么
Other fighters would do exactly what you'd say to them...
但她卻會問為什么這樣，為什么那樣 然后還是按自己的方式去做
...and she'd ask, why this and why that, and then do it her own way anyway.
她能去爭奪冠軍，我....
How she fought for the title, I...
不是靠任何....
It wasn't by anything...
不是靠聽我的話
Well, it wasn't by listening to me.
但是她現在想死
But now she wants to die...
而我只想把她留在我身邊
...and I just wanna keep her with me.
我向上帝起誓，神父
And I swear to God, Father, it's...
這樣做是犯罪
It's committing a sin by doing it.
讓她活下去，實際上是在殺死她
By keeping her alive, I'm killing her.
你明白我的意思么？ 我怎么才能克服呢？
Do you know what I mean? How do I get around that?
你不需要，你不要插手，弗蘭基
You don't. You step aside, Frankie.
把她交托給上帝
You leave her with God.
她沒有求上帝幫忙 她求我幫忙
She's not asking for God's help. She's asking for mine.
23年了，我基本上每天 都能在彌撒上見到你，弗蘭基
Frankie, I've seen you at Mass almost every day for 23 years.
只有那些為了某些事 而不能原諒自己的人
The only person comes to church that much...
才會這么頻繁地來教堂
...is the kind who can't forgive himself for something.
無論你身上背負著什么罪
Whatever sins you're carrying...
都無法和這個相提并論
...they're nothing compared to this.
忘記上帝，天堂和地獄吧
Forget about God or heaven and hell.
如果你那么做，你會迷失的
If you do this thing, you'll be lost.
深深地迷失
Somewhere so deep...
深到再也找不回自我了
...you'll never find yourself again.
我想我已經是了
I think I did it already.
我們一直給她鎮靜劑 好保證她不會再那么做
We're keeping her sedated so she won't try that again.
我今早去看了麥琪
I went to see Maggie this morning.
你一定是去了其他地方
You must have been somewhere else.
是啊
Yeah.
你在和一個我不認識的對手奮戰？
You got a fight I don't know about?
那不是你的錯
It wasn't your fault.
我當時那么說是錯誤的
I was wrong to say that.
你說得真對
You're damn right.
我給你找到一個拳手
I found you a fighter...
你讓她發揮出了最大的潛力
...and you made her the best fighter she could be.
我殺了她
I killed her.
別那么說
Don't say that.
麥琪走進那扇門的時候 除了膽量什么都沒有
Maggie walked through that door with nothing but guts.
根本沒有機會實現她的夢想
No chance in the world of being what she needed to be.
一年半以后，她在爭奪世界冠軍
A year and a half later, she's fighting for the championship of the world.
是你的功勞
You did that.
每天都有人死去的，弗蘭基
People die every day, Frankie.
拖地的時候，刷碗的時候
Mopping floors, washing dishes.
你知道他們最后一個念頭是什么嗎？
And you know what their last thought is?
“我從沒有過機會”
"I never got my shot."
因為有你，麥琪得到了屬于她的機會
Because of you, Maggie got her shot.
如果她今天就死去 你知道她最后一個念頭是什么嗎？
If she dies today, you know what her last thought will be?
“我覺得我干得不錯”
"I think I did all right."
我會覺得心安理得的
I know I could rest with that.
是啊
Yeah.
我去沖杯咖啡
I'm gonna get a cup of coffee.
好
Yeah.
好了
All right.
我會拔掉你的呼吸器...
I'm gonna disconnect your air machine...
...然后你就會睡著
...then you're gonna go to sleep.
然后我給你打一針，你就...
Then I'll give you a shot, and you'II...
...會一直睡下去
...stay asleep.
“莫 庫什勒”...
Mo cuishle...
...的意思是“我的摯愛，我的血肉”
...means "my darling, my blood."
他只給她打了一針
He gave her a single shot.
腎上腺素的劑量是需要量的好幾倍
It was enough adrenaline to do the job a few times over.
他不想讓她再受一次苦
He didn't want her going through this again.
然后他走出門去
Then he walked out.
我想他什么都沒有了
I don't think he had anything left.
我回到拳擊館
I went back to the gym.
等待著，認為他總有一天會回來
Waited, figuring he'd turn up sooner or later.
就在那時一個鬼魂走進門來
And that's when a ghost came through the door.
我想過你說的話了 斯科雷普先生
I got to thinking what you said, Mr.Scrap.
結果呢，丹吉爾？
What was that, Danger?
每個人都會失敗的
Anybody can lose one fight.
這是實話
That's the truth.
去吧，戴上手套 你已經很長時間沒訓練了
Go on, put your gloves on. You missed a lot of training.
好的，斯科雷普先生，沒問題
Will do, Mr.Scrap. Sure thing.
弗蘭基再也沒回來
Frankie never came back at all.
（兇狠是不夠的）
弗蘭基沒留下訊息 沒人知道他去了哪
Frankie didn't leave a note, and nobody knew where he went.
我希望他是去找你了
I'd hoped he'd gone to find you...
去再次請求你的原諒
...and ask you one more time to forgive him.
但也許他心中什么都沒有了
But maybe he didn't have anything left in his heart.
我只希望他能找到個地方 享受片刻的安寧
I just hope he found someplace where he could find a little peace.
一個雪松和橡樹環繞
A place set in the cedars and oak trees.
比偏僻更偏僻的地方
Somewhere between nowhere and goodbye.
但那可能只是一廂情愿
But that's probably wishful thinking.
無論他在哪兒
No matter where he is...
我想你該知道你父親 究竟是個什么樣的人
...I thought you should know what kind of man your father really was.